Orange 字幕组 原创翻译 双语字幕
翻译｜Bruna Meg　饽饽　HANA　壳壳　Rhea　雨伞　yoyo　Meoory
校对｜派派　　特效&监制｜汉斯不寂寞
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
东方快车谋杀案
一九三四年　耶路撒冷 哭墙
他四分钟前就要求了
He said four minutes precisely.
不 不 不
Non, non, non.
快点
Quickly.
这次是两个完美的鸡蛋了 是吧
Two perfect eggs this time, no?
噢
Ah.
嗯
Hmm.
也许吧
Maybe.
我怪那只鸡
I blame the chicken.
为什么母鸡们要下出不一样的蛋呢
Why do hens lay eggs of different sizes?
这不是你的错 我的朋友
It's not you, mon ami.
这是两个不错的鸡蛋
These are two perfectly good oeufs.
波洛先生…
Mr. Poirot...
三个教派处于骚乱之中
I've got three religions bent on riot.
如果你要表演你的魔法
If you're going to perform one of your miracles,
现在正是时候
the time is now.
你吃吧 我们走
Have the eggs. Allons-y!
波洛
Poirot!
不好意思 呃…
Sorry for the, um...
不是这 呃…
It is not the, uh...
是这种不平衡感…
It is the imbalance of the...
好吧
Right.
好多了
That's better.
让一下 这边走
Excuse me. Coming through.
请让一下 不好意思
Make way, please. Excuse me.
请传唤被告人
Please call for the accused.
拉比…
The rabbi...
神父…
the priest...
阿訇
and the imam.
就像过去的笑话 对吧
It is like the old joke, yes?
拉比 神父 阿訇
The rabbi, the priest, and the imam.
请原谅 我是比利时人
Forgive me, I am Belgian.
那么 让我们开始吧
So, let us begin.
就在上方的圣墓教堂里…
In the Church of the Holy Sepulchre above us...
三位代表人在警方总督察的…
three representatives meet under the supervision...
监视之下会面
of the Chief Inspector of Police
为利用集会讨论划分时间表
to discuss a divided timetable for market use.
在紧张的会面一小时后…
One hour after this tense meeting...
一个珍贵的宝物发现被窃
a priceless relic is found to be stolen.
据说是三人中的一人偷窃的
It is said, one of these three men has stolen it.
警方没有发现任何蛛丝马迹
The police find no pieces of evidence at all.
但我发现了
I find one.
在精心保存的壁画墙上…
On the meticulously well-kept wall of a fresco...
小偷在攀爬时不小心留下了一条裂缝…
a single crack from an indelicate climb...
他穿着硬底鞋或靴子
with a hard-soled shoe or perhaps a boot.
那么 女士们先生们 我们必须想想…
So, ladies and gentlemen, we must ask...
谁从此案中获益
who stands to benefit from the crime.
三位神职人员生活拮据
Our three holy men live humbly.
他们穿着薄底鞋
They're thin-soled shoes poor.
突然发横财或者拿着红宝石对他们来说太显眼了…
Sudden riches and rubies would be...
无福消受 他们不会获益
too conspicuous, yes, to enjoy. They do not gain.
此时 请一名武装守卫守在南门
At this point, we need an armed guard at the south gate.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
因此 唯一…
No, the only one...
能从偷窃以及引起的骚乱中获益的人…
who benefits from the theft and the unrest it causes...
我今早已经搜查过他的办公室了…
is a man whose office I had searched this morning...
在我等待的过程中 我不得不说
as I waited, I have to tell you,
我对早餐非常失望
rather disappointedly upon my breakfast.
尺寸不一的鸡蛋 你们没必要知道这个
Difficulty with eggs. You don't need to know this.
一个被予以重金来维持耶路撒冷秩序的人
A man who is paid lavishly to keep order in Jerusalem.
我指的当然是
I mean, of course,
警方总督察
the Chief Inspector of the Police.
他不希望失去这份待遇优厚的工作…
A man who does not wish to lose a well-paid post...
因为此时当地人
when there is discussion
正讨论着自治…
among the local peoples of self-governance...
并且他穿着靴子 我想 他正在后悔…
who does wear boots, and who, I believe, now does regret...
请我来调查这桩案子
inviting me to consult on this case.
你胆敢控告我
How dare you accuse me!
请问 军士…
Please, Sergeant...
你如我所说搜查了办公室吗
did you search the office as I asked?
是的 先生
Uh, yes, sir.
你找到我说的东西了吗
And did you find what I said you might?
是的 先生 如你所说的那样
Uh, yes, sir. Just as you said.
谢谢
Merci.
站住
Halt!
你需要递送那个 上尉
You need to deliver that, Captain.
必须要一早首先送到
It should be through first thing in the morning.
很好 先生
Very good, sir.
行李已经送上船了 先生
Luggage is on board, sir.
我很荣幸地护送您上船
I won the right to escort you to your boat.
开往伊斯坦布尔 然后呢
To Stamboul, then?
您直接回伦敦吗
Will you be back to London straight off?
我累了 我要给自己放个小长假
I am tired, and I have earned myself a little holiday.
我想去看看画展
I want to look at paintings
反正有大把时间
and have too much time on my hands.
你一直盯着我看 有事吗
You are staring. Does it stop?
我只是…
It's just...
您怎么知道是他偷的 先生
How did you know it was him, sir?
只是从墙上一个小裂缝吗
From just a tiny crack on the wall.
我有一种天赋…
I have the advantage...
我能看见世界本来的模样
I can only see the world as it should be.
当它不符合时 那种不完美感就会很突兀…
And when it is not, the imperfection stands out...
就像脸上的鼻子
like the nose in the middle of a face.
这种天赋使生活大多数时候难以忍受
It makes most of life unbearable.
但它在查案时很有用
But it is useful in the detection of crime.
感觉您看透了人们的心
But it's as though you see into their hearts
探知他们的本性
and divine their true natures.
无论人们说什么
And whatever people say,
要么是对的 要么是错的
there is right, there is wrong.
没有灰色地带
There is nothing in between.
就送到这吧
We must part here.
不 先生 我要送你上船
Oh, no, sir, I'm to escort you on the ferry.
再见 上尉
Au revoir, mon capitaine.
我们一定永远不会再见了
We must never meet again.
你能把领带戴正吗 有一点歪
Could you straighten your tie, please? Just a little.
没错 那样好多了
Yes. That is perfect.
请所有乘客上船
Final passengers, please!
噢 对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
很快就修好了
Will be fixed soon.
能及时修好吗
But, will it be fixed in time?
我们在想办法
We are working!
我要去伊斯坦布尔转火车
I have a connection in Stamboul.
明早七点开车
Leaves tomorrow at seven.
伦敦有一个重病患者在等我医治
There's a very ill patient waiting for me in London.
我是医生
I am a doctor.
医生
Doctor.
我是医生
I am a doctor.
我竟然用英语对你们吼
I am shouting at you in English,
嗓门那么大 还说的很慢
and now I'm doing it louder and slower.
真愚蠢 请原谅
Very silly, forgive me.
我能帮得上忙吗 让我帮忙吧
May I help? Let me help.
我认得你的胡子
I know your mustache.
在报纸上
From the papers.
你是那个侦探 赫勒克勒斯 波洛
You're the detective, Hercules Poirot?
赫尔克里 波洛 你说的那位是杀死狮子的大力神 小姐
Hercule Poirot. I do not slay the lions. Mademoiselle.
我叫玛丽 德贝纳姆 先生
Mary Debenham, monsieur.
我可能会记错名字但是不会认错脸的
I'll forget a name but never a face.
至少你的脸我不会认错
Not yours, anyway.
你从巴格达来的
You come from Baghdad?
没错 果真没什么能逃开你的法眼
It's true. No detail escapes his notice.
是你的车票
Your ticket. Ah.
还想请问您在那边担任家庭教师…
I might also ask you if you enjoyed your time there...
还算愉快吧
as a governess?
你袖子上的粉笔和地理读物
The chalk on your sleeve and the geography primer.
家庭女教师或是绘图者 我猜了一个
A governess or a cartographer. I made my gamble.
我总是从地理开始教起…
I always begin them with geography...
逼着他们把世界装进脑子
and monster them till they have the world down cold.
他们也许会在生活中迷失…
They may get lost in life...
但绝不可能不知道自己身在何处
but I'll be damned if they don't know where they are.
麻烦解决了 时间刚好
Well, our chains are free. Right on time.
在海上我感到无比自由
I feel so free out here on the water.
我希望可以享受这段旅途
I wish I could enjoy it.
我们不该牵涉进去 玛丽
We should be out of this, Mary.
现在不行
Not now.
等一切都结束了
When it's all over.
等事成之后
When it's done.
没什么能阻挡我们了
Then, nothing can touch us.
伊斯坦布尔
噢 我的假期从此开始了
Ah, my holiday begins here.
我能从这些朴实的烤饼中 看见城市之魂
I can see the soul of the city in these humble breads.
世界不断走向毁灭 而在这里…
The world insists on destruction, yet here...
每天这些杰作被有序地烘烤出来
masterpieces are baked to order every day.
波洛先生
Monsieur Poirot!
穆罕默德
Mohammed!
穆罕默德 我的朋友…
Mohammed, my friend...
你真是个艺术家
you are an artist.
噢 我的朋友
Ah! My friend!
不好意思
Sorry.
这儿 来
Here. Come, come.
别管我们 我们只是在找
Don't mind us, we're just looking
一个可以私下探讨的地方
for a place to have a private argument.
只需要二十分钟或者…
It should take some 20 minutes or so...
我们就能
at which point we will both
达成一致 至少我可以
come to an agreement, or at least I will.
布克先生
Monsieur Bouc!
波洛 居然在厨房里见到你
Poirot! In the kitchen?
当然 这位先生嗅到
Well, of course, this man will sniff out
美味烤饼的速度比他…
a perfect pastry faster than he catches...
抓住一个珠宝大盗还要快
a jewel thief.
我的朋友
Mon ami!
我现在不是警探了
Now, I am no longer a policeman.
你再搞事情的话我就捞不出你了
I cannot bail you out when this goes badly, eh?
这是我亲爱的老朋友 尊敬的…
This is my dear, old friend, the esteemed...
波洛 在他出名前我们就认识了
Poirot, who I knew before the esteem.
赫尔克里·波洛 这是…
Hercule Poirot, this is...
一个妓女 没错
A prostitute. She is.
我是 布克 你从没说过你有这么大名鼎鼎的朋友
I am. Bouc, you did not tell me you had famous friends.
我们成为朋友是因为
We're friends because
我是唯一一个不会问他…
I'm the only person who never asks him...
任何关于案子的问题 因为我不在乎
any questions about his cases, because I don't care.
而且他从不会因为我差劲而嫌弃我
And he never judges me for being a terrible person.
你确实很差劲
Indeed you are.
女士 布克 一起喝一杯吧
Madame, Bouc, please join me for a drink, yes?
我只能陪你一小时
You only have me for an hour.
七点我就要上东方快车
I ride on the Orient Express at seven,
我担任总监
official director business.
我叔叔付了一大笔钱
Uncle pays me absurdly
让我在他豪华的火车上工作…
to stay onboard his gorgeous train...
并且离他的总部…
and far away from him...
很远…
at the home office...
置身于美酒佳肴之中
consigned to wine and dine
与美人权贵宴饮
handsome officials for all eternity.
裙带关系也是门艺术
There is an art to nepotism.
而你是其中的大师
And you are its Michelangelo!
波洛先生
Mr. Poirot.
你也是个妓女吗
Are you a prostitute as well?
当然不是
Certainly not.
这个人烦到你了吗
Is this man bothering you?
快了
He is about to.
你是英国领事馆的人
You are from the British consulate.
是的 先生 是卡斯纳的案子
I am, sir. It is the Kassner case.
您怎么知道的
Why, yes.
我猜的没错吧
I was correct in certain predictions?
完全正确
Quite.
我不需要读这个电报
I do not need to read the telegram.
噢 有意思
Oh, how fun.
有人出轨 还是死亡了
Did someone cheat, or die?
很不幸 两者都是
Unfortunately, both.
有人…
Someone has...
打断了我休息的计划
interrupted my longing for rest.
看来我今晚必须和你一起走了 布克
It appears that I must travel with you tonight, Bouc.
你能帮我在东方快车上找个车厢吗
Can you find me a cabin on the Orient Express?
我的朋友…
My friend...
别的不好说 但我绝对
I may not be good for much, but I sure as hell
能在我的火车上给你找张床…
can get you a bed on my train...
大冬天里三天的行程…
in the dead of winter. Three days...
无忧无虑 摆脱一切案子 你会爱上它的
free of care, concern or crime. You will love it.
女士 很高兴认识你
Mademoiselle, it has been a pleasure. Sir.
您的行李已经取走了
Your luggage has been collected
车费也付了
and your expenses paid.
您在加来下车…
You will be met at Calais...
有人会送您到多佛
and then escorted to Dover,
然后再坐火车到伦敦维多利亚站
and then by rail to London Victoria.
我想向您郑重表示感谢
I would like to formally express gratitude.
请别说了
Please, don't speak.
说得我心烦
You make it worse.
- 这是你的小费 伙计  - 谢谢 马奎兹先生
- Here's a tip for you, pal.  - Thank you, Mr. Marquez.
我都没帮您搬行李
I didn't even carry your luggage.
噢 我这周过得不错
Oh, I had a good week.
走运的时候就得庆祝
We celebrate when fortune smiles,
我们要分享好运
and we share the good fortune.
记得要说我们美国人的好话哈
Remember to say nice things about us Americans, huh?
滚
No!
嘿 站住
Hey, stop!
晚上好 先生
Monsieur, bonsoir.
雷切特先生
For you, Mr. Ratchett,
为您准备了我们这最好的位置
the best table in the house.
在这边 先生 最好的位置
Just here, sir. The very best table.
不 我要坐在这
No, I want that one.
嘿 马思特曼 都安排好了吗
Hey, Masterman. You got everything?
那还用问吗 麦奎因先生
Kind of you to inquire, Mr. MacQueen.
我从不犯错
I do not make mistakes.
哦天啊 是安德烈伯爵
Oh, my goodness! It's Count Andrenyi.
快过来
Come, come, come.
我看过你在蒙特克里斯托跳舞
I saw you dance at the Monte Cristo.
我能给你拍张照吗
Could I take your photograph?
求你了 别打脸
Please, my face, no!
抱歉
Sorry.
东方快车…
The Simplon Orient Express...
经停索非亚 尼什 贝尔格莱德 温科夫齐 布罗德…
with stops in Sofia, Niš, Belgrade, Vinkovci, Brod...
可中转至布加勒斯特 萨格勒布
with transfers to Bucharest, Zagreb,
的里雅斯特 威尼斯 米兰 洛桑…
Trieste, Venezia, Milan, Lausanne...
第戎 巴黎 布伦 加来…
Dijon, Paris, Boulogne, Calais...
可前往多佛及伦敦
with connection to Dover and London,
十五分钟后出发
leaves in fifteen minutes!
这边 米歇尔 来贵客了
This way, Michel! Precious cargo.
我需要一张头等车票
I need a first-class compartment.
好好照顾我的朋友 米歇尔
Give special care to my friend, Michel.
像国宝大熊猫一样的待遇
I want him pampered like a zoo panda.
可是布克先生 席位已经满了
But Monsieur Bouc, we are fully booked.
没有位置了
There's no space left.
想办法腾出来 可以安排十一号包厢
Then we make space. He can have the number eleven.
那里一般都安排给公务人员
The eleven is always kept open for official use.
非常舒适
It's very comfortable.
十一号有人了
Eleven is taken.
两天前一名奥地利教授预定的
The Austrian professor booked it two days ago.
整趟列车就找不到一个
There is not one first-class
头等包厢吗
sleeper car on the whole train?
找不到 先生
Negative, sir.
- 二等座呢  - 没位置了
- Second-class?  - There's no space left at all.
德贝纳姆小姐
Mademoiselle Debenham.
波洛先生 您也坐这趟列车吗
Mr. Poirot, are you joining us?
那得看他们俩谁说得赢谁
It depends who wins this debate.
所有的乘客都到了吗
Have all the passengers arrived?
还差一位 哈里斯先生
All but one. Mr. Harris.
“所有乘客必须至少
"All passengers must check in
提前半个小时检票…
At least one half hour prior to time of departure...
否则座位可能被收回”
Or their seat may be forfeit."
已经不到半小时了 收回座位
The half hour has passed. The seat is forfeit.
请把波洛先生的行李
Please take Monsieur Poirot's luggage
送到三号包厢 和麦奎因先生一间
to number three with Mr. MacQueen.
谢谢 布克 旅途愉快 我的朋友
Merci, Bouc. Enjoy, my friend.
欢迎您先生 谢谢
Welcome, sir. Merci.
数字“三”可不吉利
Number three is unlucky.
抱歉女生 刚才无意冒犯
Apologies, madame. I meant no disrespect.
冒犯一下也没关系
Well, you could try to mean a little.
坐火车出行有一点
One thing about train travel,
难免会碰到一些人
you're always knocking into somebody.
很有趣
It's wonderful.
不过我还是想回去
Though, I am looking forward to getting back.
我爱旅行 爱辛辣的美食 异域风情 浪漫邂逅
Travel is fine for spicy food, mosques, meeting men.
但最终还是想念自己的床
But eventually, you just miss your own bed.
肯定有人会说我总是满世界地找老公
I've been accused of husband hunting abroad.
不过我还真不否认这点
Well, I can't, in all honesty, deny it.
虽然我喜欢独处 我是说真的
I like my time alone, I do.
不过 一个女人如果有钱的话
But a lady has certain needs
她的需求就该被满足…
that deserve to be met if she has any money...
最好还是定期满足
and preferably, on a regular basis.
天呐 厨房着火了
Oh, my! Fire in the kitchen!
再会了 女士
Farewell, madame.
晚上好
Good evening.
Bonsoir.
九号
Number nine.
晚上好
Good evening. Bonsoir, bonsoir.
你好吗 晚上好
How you doing? Bonsoir.
哦不好意思
Oh. Excusez-moi.
您先
No, after you.
谢谢
Merci, merci.
三号到了
Ah number three.
你是麦奎因先生吗
You are Mr MacQueen?
我想你走错包厢了
Yeah. I think you might have the wrong berth.
抱歉 有什么问题吗先生
Sorry, is there a problem sir?
没问题
No, no problem.
列车满了
The train is full.
我想我们 怎么说…算是室友了
I think that we are, how do you say... "Bunkies."
是吗
Really?
我也觉得很失望 这还不错
I am equally disappointed in you. This is nice.
跟上 宝贝儿
Come along, darlings.
不行
No.
这间呢
This?
怎么行李还没送来
Why am I not yet unpacked?
五分钟后发车
Five minutes to departure.
最后一次通知乘客
Final call for passengers!
我们要不要给你梳毛啊
Shall we brush you?
他们怎么磨蹭这么久
What the hell is taking them so long?
发车后让他们赶紧铺床
Soon as we get out of here, have them make up the bed.
都安排好了 雷切特先生
It's already arranged, Mr. Ratchett.
不 先把床铺好 再把我的录音机拿来
No, I want the bed made. And bring my Dictaphone.
连狗狗都上桌了
Dogs on the table.
真是我见过最恶心的事
Most disgusting thing I've ever seen in my life.
是的 先生 你去找麦奎因…
Yes, sir. I want you to get MacQueen...
让他把米兰那笔买卖的单据全都拿来
and have him bring every receipt from the Milan sale.
现在就去 好的先生
I want you to get it done. Yes, sir.
现在就去
I want you to get it done now.
不是让你马上就去吗 这就去 先生
Did I say get it done now? Right away, sir.
“你最好小心点”
"Better watch yourself."
您的咖啡 雷切特先生
Your coffee, Mr. Ratchett.
这是谁干的
Who did this?
我不知道 先生
I can't say, sir.
晚上好 哈伯德夫人
Good evening, Mrs. Hubbard.
你好 马斯特曼
Hello there, Mr. Masterman.
你好
Well, hello.
你再这么看下去 我就要收费了
Eyes linger any longer, I'll have to charge rent.
我很乐意付钱
I'll pay.
再来一杯吧
Mmm. Have another drink.
让您受辱了吗
Are you insulted?
只是有点失望罢了
Hmm. Disappointed.
有些人长得好看
Some men have a good look.
他们需要做的…
All they have to do is...
仅仅是把嘴闭上
keep their mouth shut,
就可以有所作为
and they can take home any prize they want.
可惜不 偏偏要开口说话
Still, the mouth opens.
没事吧 哈伯德夫人
Is everything all right, Mrs. Hubbard?
我觉得您的直觉非常敏锐
You have a strong intuition, I know.
我第二任丈夫也这么说
My second husband used to say just so.
等等 应该是第一任
Hold that, it was my first.
没错
Yeah.
他是我见过的最聪明的人
Brightest man I ever met.
长得像萝卜一样 不过我曾爱过那颗萝卜
Face like a turnip, but I loved that turnip.
和您聊天很愉快
It was nice to talk.
晚安
Good night.
波洛先生
Monsieur Poirot?
请进 米歇尔
Entrez, Pierre Michel.
您醒了
Voilà.
晚餐时…
When you take supper...
我会把麦奎因先生的东西
I will move Monsieur MacQueen
搬到布克先生的包厢
into Monsieur Bouc's compartment.
您享受头等舱待遇
You travel first class, monsieur.
太棒了 谢谢
Ah, impeccable. Merci.
用餐愉快
Bon appétit.
…这个鸡蛋
...and the eggs?
下午好
Good afternoon.
哈伯德夫人
Ah, Mrs. Hubbard.
下午好
Good afternoon.
请慢用
There we are.
敬我们乘坐的东方快车
Compliments of the Orient Express.
谢谢 布克先生
Thank you, Mr. Bouc.
有什么需要 随时告诉我
I am here for all of your needs.
不 谢谢 我不喝酒
No, thank you. I do not drink.
您不喜欢喝酒吗
It does not agree with you?
我只是想远离罪恶
Sin does not agree with me.
恶习永远都是魔鬼的伙伴
Vice is where the devil finds his darlings.
那我就不打扰您了
We should no longer speak.
下午好
Good afternoon.
先生 要不要来杯开胃酒
Monsieur. How about a apéritif?
可惜我已经和火车上的负责人
I regret I have an appointment
约好了见面
with the director of the train.
他很快就要走了
He was gonna leave anyway.
没事 先生 女士您好
Please, sir. Madame, madame.
女士 女士
Madame, madame.
都安顿好了吗
All settled in?
都安排好了 都如广告所说那样
Ah, merci! As advertised.
不过 车上最好的可不是食物
And yet, the best things on the train are not food.
而是一群陌生人…
You know there's something about...
缘分使然坐上了同一趟列车
a tangle of strangers pressed together
一待就是几天…
for days on end, with nothing in common...
除此之外 毫无联系…
but the need to go from one place to another...
下车后就再也不见
then never to see each other again.
闲来无聊碰上萍水相逢…
Boredom plus anonymity plus a...
再配上这曼妙的晃动
constant, gentle rocking.
就你这样很难成大事
With your hobbies, you will never amount to anything.
我倒希望是这样
God, I hope so. Hmm.
我要点道鱼
Order me the fish.
把石斑鱼换成比目鱼
Um, exchange grouper for sole,
再把莴苣换成土豆…
escarole for the potato, and...
还有 牛肉汤换成骨汤
the beef sauce for the velouté.
服务员 这听上去很棒 给我也来一份
Garéon, that sounds superb. The same for me.
德拉戈米罗夫公主
The Princess Dragomiroff.
如果我为了钱和人结婚
You know, if I ever were to marry for money,
就找她这么有钱的
I'd marry for that much money.
早上我给达莉娅梳了毛
I brushed Dalia this morning.
不 我让你给我的小狗梳毛
No, you tortured my darling doggy.
你却在折磨她
I asked you to brush her.
你还是爱看狄更斯的书吗
Are you still enjoying your Dickens?
当然了 我的朋友
Very much, mon ami.
你这样光顾着看书和破案
You know, with your books and your capers,
很容易就错过艳遇
you are missing out on romance.
艳遇都是要付出代价的
Romance never goes unpunished.
我以前…
There was, uh...
也爱过一个人
There was someone once.
我希望之后别再让我坐在那个人旁边了
I would prefer, in the future, to be sat not with that man.
物以类聚 人以群分
Like should be seated with like.
我们并不是一类人
We are not alike.
不是所有人都会
Not all of us are so concerned
那么在意种族差异 教授
with the separateness of races, Professor.
我的坚持完全是
It is out of respect for all kinds
出于对所有种族的尊重
that I prefer to keep them separate.
如果把红酒和白酒混在一起
To mix your red wine and the white
两者就都毁了
would be to ruin them both.
我喜欢桃红酒
I like a good rosé.
你好吗 不介意…
Hey, how you doing? Would you mind...
我坐在这里吧
if I joined you?
甜品是一种享受…
Dessert is an indulgence...
一个人独享就实在太蠢了
and I feel kinda silly and stupid indulging alone.
我一个人待着挺好的
I am at my happiest alone.
不过…
But...
看在你这份丹麦卷的份上
for a small piece of your fragelité,
一起吧
please join me.
好的 不好意思 再拿把叉子
Oh, with pleasure. Excuse me, another fork?
我一直想找机会认识你 波洛先生
I've been trying to make your acquaintance, Mr. Poirot.
谢谢
Merci.
我从来没有这么近距离的接触过名人
I never ever sat so close to fame before.
不对我说谎了
No, I tell a lie.
我曾和泰·柯布坐过一辆车
Once, I was on a bus with Ty Cobb.
底特律的球员
Ball player, Detroit. Ah.
你不介意我把顶上这些吃掉吧
Would you mind if I have the little curly bit at the top?
你还挺奇葩的
You're an odd bird there.
真是一个怪人
You're a strange, peculiar man.
到了这把年纪
I am of an age
我很清楚自己想要什么 不要什么
where I know what I like and what I do not like.
喜欢的东西尽情享受
What I like, I enjoy enormously.
不喜欢的绝不容忍
What I dislike, I cannot abide.
比如 谈生意前 人们都爱说的
For instance, the temporary pleasantries
那些客套话 我就很讨厌
before what is determined to be a business discussion.
你很有趣
You're fun.
好吧
All right.
我想雇你做一件事
I would like to offer you a job.
报纸称呼您为
"The avenger of the innocent."
“为清白而战的复仇者”
It's what they call you in the papers.
你是清白之人吗
And you are an innocent?
我是个商人
I'm a businessman.
我是个艺术商人 我是说 我还是个新手
I'm an art dealer. I mean, I'm new to it.
但是刚开始运气就挺好的
But my beginner's luck has panned out.
文物 古董
Relics, antiquities.
地毯 奇怪的玩意 东方的物品
Rugs, weird. Orientals.
我是刚入行的 所以眼光有些业余
I'm new to the game, so I got the amateur eyeball.
不过我觉得那些 呃…
But I got a little problem with these, uh...
所谓的鉴定师有点儿问题
so-called appraisers.
其中任何一个都不能相信
You can't trust a one of 'em.
我的一些顾客…
Some of my customers...
他们买了点东西…
they buy a piece...
然后发现那些东西是赝品…
they find out that they're not exactly original...
不能说是我的错…
which is hardly my fault...
谁知道卡香丝绸围巾是假货
if a Kashan silk scarf is a fake.
对吧
Right? Huh?
没错
C'est bon.
但事情是我结下了点儿梁子
But I've managed to make a few enemies, is the thing.
我收到一些信 有人在威胁我
I got a few letters, people making threats.
我认为 很可能是那些意大利人
I think, most likely, it's the Italians.
我在米兰卖给他们一套东方地毯
I sold them a set of Oriental carpets in Milan.
然而买家对其来源不是很满意
And the buyers weren't so happy with the provenance.
他们想要把本钱和利润都要回去 你懂吧
And they want their money back with interest, you know?
意大利人
Italians.
他们就是这样
A guinea's a guinea.
接着迎面而来一位大侦探
And then comes along the genius detective.
我吗
Me?
- 是的 就是你 赫拉克勒斯 波罗  - 赫尔克里
- Yes, you. Hercules Poirot.  - Hercule.
呃…
Um...
我要说我想要做的事情
Here's what I'd like to do.
我想要雇你保护我…
I would like to hire you to watch my back...
直到我安全到达某地
until I get someplace safe.
这对你来说是很容易到手的钱
It's easy money for you.
我也是为了心安 你知道吧
And it's peace of mind for me, you know?
我明白了 很好
I understand. Good.
我拒绝
I refuse.
抱歉 那就不好了
I'm sorry? That's bad.
或许我说的不够清楚
Maybe I didn't make myself clear enough.
你看 有人要对我不利
You see, someone's out to get me.
我知道我并不是什么好人 也绝不可能是
And I know I'm not the best guy born, not by a long shot.
如果死后有另一个世界
And if there's a world after this one,
我会和你一样面临审判
I will face judgment just like you.
但是…
But...
我还不急着去那儿
I ain't in no goddamn rush to do it.
你在拿枪指着我吗 不是
You're holding a gun on me? No.
不是你 是这个世界
Not you. On the world.
我存在于世界 不要用枪指着我
I exist in the world. Do not point a gun at me.
一个星期一万如何
How's ten thousand sound for a week?
确实慷慨 雷切特先生 我必须拒绝
It's a generous offer, Mr. Ratchett. I must decline.
一万五呢
Fifteen thousand?
你没听见我的说的 我拒绝
You didn't hear me. I decline.
噢 我懂了
Oh, I get it.
对于伟大的赫拉克勒斯 波罗来说 这事儿不够光彩 是吧
It's not flashy enough for the great Hercules Poirot, huh?
没有闪光灯…
No flashbulbs...
你卖假货给匪徒
You sell fakes to gangsters.
你得承担后果
You're suffering the consequences.
我找出罪犯 但我不保护他们
I detect criminals. I do not protect them.
所以你是拒绝我的脏钱
So you say "No" To my dirty money.
我是拒绝你 雷切特先生
I say "No" To you, Mr. Ratchett.
是枪的事儿 对吧 就是这个吗
Business with the gun, right? Is that what it was?
更多的是个人原因
It is far more personal than that.
我不喜欢你的脸
I do not like your face.
请允许我先行离开
If you will excuse me.
你喜欢我的蛋糕 对吧
You liked my cake, didn't you?
蛋糕棒极了
The cake was excellent.
祝您有个愉快的下午 雷切特先生
Have a pleasant afternoon, Mr. Ratchett.
谢谢你
Thank you.
噢 真是冷
Ooh! Cold.
唔
Hmm.
心爱的凯瑟琳
Mysweet Katherine.
我的爱
My love.
狄更斯先生
Mr. Dickens.
雷切特先生
Mr. Ratchett?
没事
It's nothing.
好的 先生
Very good sir.
晚安
Good night.
哈伯德夫人吗
Mrs. Hubbard?
是哈伯德夫人
It's always Mrs. Hubbard.
哈伯德夫人
Mrs. Hubbard.
我们都死了吗
Did we die?
女士们先生们 列车脱轨了
Ladies and gentlemen, the train has been derailed.
你一切都好吗 马奎兹先生
Are you all right, Mr. Marquez?
我很好 谢谢
I'm fine. Thank you.
待在车厢里是最安全的
You'll be safest in your cabins.
布克先生明早…
Mr. Bouc will speak to you all...
会和大家说明
in the morning.
请待在车厢里 那是最安全的
Please, you will be safest in your cabins.
当然
Of course.
我们要死了吗
Are we gonna die?
噢…
Oh...
我的凯瑟琳
MyKatherine.
我美丽的…
Mybeautiful...
女士们先生们 我很抱歉
Ladies and gentlemen, I am afraid
我们的列车依然无法行动
that our train is still unable to go anywhere.
是的 快要掉下去了
Yeah, except down.
我们还要在这儿待多久呢
How long are we supposed to just sit here?
是啊 得有人做点儿什么
Yes, someone must be doing something.
我确实做了点事儿 我什么也不用做
Of course I am doing something. I am doing nothing.
准确来说两个小时十分钟之前
Precisely two hours and ten minutes ago,
当我们没有按时到达布罗德…
when we did not arrive in Brod as scheduled...
站长必定会猜到我们的处境…
the station master will have surmised our situation...
他已经派遣一队人来挖掘引擎…
and already dispatched a team to excavate the engine...
为我们清理道路 然后让我们能再次踏上旅程
clear our path, and send us on our way.
在那之前 我保证…
Until then, I assure you...
我们会为你们提供充足的食物和温暖舒适的服务
we will all be made warm and fed and comfortable.
我们可以步行
We could walk.
我们会在冷风中被冻死
We could die of exposure trying.
我还要换乘呢
I have a connection to make.
我的船后天就从法国出发了
My boat sails day after tomorrow from France.
我打赌你上不了船 我也到不了伦敦
Without you, I'd wager. Or me in London.
我希望你能对我损失的时间负责 布克先生
I hold you accountable for my loss of time, Mr. Bouc.
女士 你不能让我对这种天气负责
Madam, you cannot hold me accountable for the weather.
我当然可以 谁让你是负责人
Of course I can. You're the one here.
我在都灵的会议怎么办
And my conference in Turin?
我还要去索肖的汽车工厂和人会面呢
And I was to meet at the auto factory in Sochaux.
是的 有些事情 是掌握在上帝手上的
Yes, some things, they are in God's hands.
我们是否能安全抵达目的地…
It is not for us to say...
不是我们说了算的…
if we deserve to arrive safely at our destination...
撒旦：路西法，传说中的堕落天使
或者像撒旦我们注定堕落
or if, like Lucifer, we must fall.
您的早餐 雷切特先生
Breakfast for you, Mr. Ratchett.
啊 你好 马斯特曼先生
Ah, Bonjour, Mr. Masterman.
有什么问题吗
There is a problem?
我没法确定 先生
I can't say, sir.
雷切特先生
Mr. Ratchett?
抱歉
Excuse me.
有冷风
That is cold air.
请立刻让布克先生过来
Please bring Monsieur Bouc immediately,
还有阿巴斯诺特医生
and also Dr. Arbuthnot.
老天爷啊
Good God!
除了尸体 什么也不要碰
Touch nothing else, only the body.
我的天 太可怕了
My God, this is horrible.
先是暴风雪 现在又是…
First the snow, now...
我得去站台通知警方
I'll have to meet with the police
并说明情况
and make some statement in some grimy station.
有个人死在这儿了
And a man has died.
有人死在这里
他是被捅死的
He was stabbed.
是一把长刀
Long, straight-edged knife.
身上有多处伤口 有些很浅
Multiple stab wounds, some shallow,
有些直插入肌肉
some cut clean through muscle.
左撇子还是右撇子
Left-hand side or right-hand side?
这是个问题
That's the thing.
这个凶手可能
It appears the killer
闭上了眼睛然后摸黑捅的
maybe closed his eyes and struck blind.
你能估算出死亡时间吗
Can you estimate the time of death?
窗户开着很难推算出时间…
It's hard to say with the window open...
但是很有可能是在午夜和凌晨两点之间
but my best guess is between midnight and 2:00.
但是那个时候没有人进入他的车厢
But no one went in his compartment then.
我整夜都在站岗
I sat in my seat all night.
如果有人进去我肯定会看见 这不可能
I would have seen if someone went in. It's impossible.
谢谢你 医生 请回餐车吧
Thank you, Doctor. Please, return to the dining car.
米歇尔 保护这个车厢
Michel, secure this carriage.
波罗
Poirot.
我需要你的帮助 我的朋友
I need your help, my friend.
你得找出是谁干的
You have to find who did this.
拜托了 我代表
Please, I implore you,
东方快车恳求你
on behalf of the Orient Express.
在警察到的时候
When the police arrive,
我们能够告诉他们事件已经解决了
we can present them with the case closed.
只有你能够救我了
You are the only one who can save me.
你的真诚打动了我 亲爱的
Your faith touches me, mon cher.
但是我必须好好享受假期
But I must have this rest.
那就把它当作在海滨的小游戏
Well, think of it as a little beachside puzzle.
对你来说不算什么
That's nothing to your mind!
你查看一下那些乘客的经历
You look up the antecedents of the passengers.
看他们有没有说实话
You establish their bona fides.
你就做你该做的 你…你…
Then you do what you do. You... You... You...
你就坐在椅子上吃着蛋糕…
You sit in a chair and you eat your cake...
然后思考着直到真相浮出水面
and you think until the solution presents itself.
不然坐在冰天雪地里还能干什么
What else are you going to do while we sit here in the snow?
头脑没有连续的刺激
Without constant stimulation,
你的脑细胞会饿死的
your little gray cells will starve and die.
你觉得那就是我要做的吗 坐在椅子上…
You think that is what I do? I sit in a chair...
吃着一小块蛋糕
and I have a little piece of cake,
然后我就能想到一个很好的办法了吗
and then I come up with a great idea?
我不知道你是如何处理的 我有我的狄更斯
I don't know what you do. I have my Dickens.
去你的狄更斯吧
Damn your Dickens!
如果我们把这个留给警察
If we leave this to the police,
他们会找出一个凶手…
they will choose a culprit...
不管对与错 他们会吊死他
right or wrong, and they will hang him.
很可能是马奎兹先生…
Most probably Mr. Marquez...
只因为他的名字叫做马奎兹
for no other reason than his name is Marquez.
或者是阿巴斯诺特医生 因为他的肤色
Or Dr. Arbuthnot for the color of his skin.
你是唯一可以带来正义的人
You are the only one who can bring justice.
给我一张列车的地图
Let me have a map of this coach.
没问题
Of course.
每一位乘客的通行证 所有的一切
Every passport. Anything.
安排和所有乘客进行面谈
Interviews arranged with all of our passengers.
搜集证据 理清顺序 找出方法 直到凶手出现
Evidence, order and method, until one culprit emerges.
我不能容忍谋杀 我的朋友
I do not approve of murder, my friend.
我们每天都会遇到
Every day, we meet people
一些没有他们世界会变得更好的人…
the world could do better without...
然而我们不能杀死他们
yet we do not kill them.
我们不能和野兽相提并论
We must be better than the beasts.
所以让我们找到这个凶手
So let us find this killer.
发生什么了
What's going on?
女士们先生们 允许我 呃…
Ladies and gentlemen, allow me to, um...
似乎我们的运气更加糟糕了
It appears that our bad luck has worsened.
有…
That is...
一名乘客死在了列车上
A passenger has died on the train.
雷切特先生
Monsieur Ratchett.
看起来他们最后还是出手了
Looks like they got him after all.
你觉得他是被杀的吗
You assume he was killed?
不 不
No, no.
我只是说他身体十分健康
I just mean he was in perfectly good health.
然后他树敌很多 就这样
He had his enemies, that's all.
确实是这样 他被杀死了
Indeed, he did. He was murdered.
我的老天 谋杀 发生在这儿吗
Good God. Murder, here?
很不幸 女士
Alas, madame.
愿上帝保佑他的灵魂安息
God rest his soul.
有人半夜在我的车厢里
Someone was rummaging around my cabin
翻找东西
in the middle of the night.
没有人相信我
Nobody would believe me.
现在是什么情况
What is going on?
就在我们被雪困住之际
As we are snowbound,
我已经受我的朋友布克先生的委托…
I have elected to take the case...
接手这个案件并找出凶手
and find for my friend, Monsieur Bouc, the criminal.
为什么是你
And why you?
我是赫拉克勒斯 波罗…
My name is Hercule Poirot...
我可能是世界上最伟大的侦探
and I am probably the greatest detective in the world.
我会及时找你们谈话
I will speak to all of you in time.
现在…
For the moment...
我必须建议你们待在
I must recommend that you remain
车厢内并把门锁好
in your compartments with the doors locked.
我觉得跟个囚犯一样
I feel like a prisoner here.
这是为你们自身的安全着想
It is for your own safety.
如果发生了一起谋杀案…
If there was a murder...
那就有一个凶手
then there was a murderer.
而凶手在我们身边…
The murderer is with us...
就在列车上 就现在
on the train, now.
两个车厢之前的门在晚上是锁着的对吗
The doors between coaches were locked at night, hmm?
当然 我亲自锁的
Absolutely. Done myself.
列车已经被搜查了
The train's been searched.
列车上下都没人躲着
There's no one hiding on it or under it.
这样我们就可以缩小我们搜索的范围
We can therefore limit our investigation
至加来车厢的乘客
to the occupants of the Calais coach.
布克 你来协助我
Bouc, you will assist me.
因为你是唯一在另一个车厢住的乘客…
As the only traveler who slept in another coach...
你是唯一没有嫌疑的人
you are the only one who is not a suspect.
麦奎因先生 现在是喝酒的时候吗
Mr. MacQueen, is this really the time for drinking?
我老板死了
My boss is dead.
我失业了
I'm out of a job,
然后你感觉是我干的一样
and you're looking at me like I did it.
我们还没有定论
We make no accusations.
你认识他
You knew him, so from here
所以现在我们有必要整理一下重要事实
we must glean the essential facts.
你是他的亲戚吗
Were you his relative?
不是 我是秘书
No, his secretary.
我给他订票 定餐
Book his travel, order his steaks.
我从没见过像这样
The man ate more steak
吃这么多牛排的人
than I've ever seen in my entire life.
他以前做古董生意
He was in antiques.
没有售卖资格证
He had no qualification for it,
没有做生意的眼色和说辞
not the eye or the languages.
事实上 他没有经商 或是会计头脑…
Truth is, he had no head for business, accounting...
没有
none of it.
我解决所有事情
I took care of everything.
他雇佣你多久了
How long were you in his employ?
还有二十天就满一年了
Twenty days shy of a year.
我不喜欢禁令…
Prohibition wasn't to my taste...
所以当我醒悟时 我一人在海外还负着债
so I found myself overseas, and in debt.
我学的法律…
I'm a lawyer by education...
但不是职业律师
not disposition.
我十分不擅长这行业
I was downright awful at it.
你喜欢他吗
You were fond of him?
我喜欢他的钱
I was fond of his money.
雷切特是个蛮人…
Ratchett was crude...
要求苛刻 辱骂他人 几乎像个囚徒
demanding, insulting, and most likely a felon.
你上次见他是什么时候
When did you last see him?
那肯定是十点以后了
It must have been just after 10:00.
他让我汇报我们在意大利的销售情况
He called me in to go over our sales in Italy.
在米兰 销售伪造证件
Milan, the sale of forgeries?
对
Yeah, yeah.
他想看账单
He wanted to look over the accounts.
我什么都得翻译给他…
I had to translate everything...
因为合同是法语
as the contracts were in French
他法语都不会打招呼
and he didn't speak a word.
然后当我们在温科夫齐下站的时候…
And when we stopped at Vinkovci...
我们和一个不是白人的医生聊起来了 姓阿巴斯诺特
I struck up a chat with the colored doctor, Arbuthnot.
然后我们喝了会 伸伸懒腰
And we had a couple of drinks, stretched our legs.
他有一些…
He had some...
我不赞同的关于斯大林的意见
odd opinions about Stalin I had to turn around.
我不因一个人的宗族而而他作对
I don't hold a man's race against him,
但是我不信任英国人
but I don't often take to Britishers.
你们什么时候和他分手的
When did your party end?
他两点之后就走了
He left just after 2:00.
你知道雷切特有可能会有的
Did you know of any specific enemies
具体敌人吗
Ratchett might have had?
老天
Gosh.
说说多少
Pick a number.
他曾透露过收到威胁消息
He confided he had been threatened?
他收到了一些威胁信
He got a couple of nasty letters.
如果你们想要的话 我有
I have them if you like. Some, anyway.
他把剩下的撕了
He tore up the rest.
烧干净了
Threw them into the fire.
这是剩下的
That's them.
你最好自己当心点
除了咱俩 没人能懂
谢谢 麦奎因先生
Merci, Mr. MacQueen.
嗯 谢谢
Uh, thank you.
如果你还有问题
If we have any further questions,
我们会给你打电话的
we will call for you again.
你考虑过那个拉丁裔的男人吗
Have you considered the Latin man?
马奎兹 可怕的家伙
Marquez. Hell of a guy.
而且 他这种人…
And, well, you know, his kind...
他们并不厌恶杀戮
they don't have the same distaste for murder,
从历史上来讲
historically speaking.
你说了要公正对待每个种族的人
You said you don't hold a man's race against him.
我觉得…
I suppose...
还是要看看什么种族
depends on the race.
他还看起来很淡定
And he was doing so well.
你觉得是麦奎因先生 太早定论了
You think it's MacQueen? Too early to say.
我承认 我看不透他
I admit, I cannot see him
把一个人疯狂的捅十二刀
stabbing a man twelve times in a frenzy.
肯定不清醒 是谁呢
Not sober, anyway. Who did it then?
我还不知道 这时候我们该问问题了
I do not know yet. It is time we ask.
问谁 受害者
Ask who? The victim.
他被捅了十二刀
He has twelve stab wounds
然后 阿巴斯诺特说 是无规律的伤口
and, as Arbuthnot said, they are patternless.
如果是医生杀人…
If the doctor is guilty...
他确实没有影响
he certainly did not let it influence
他做医生的职责
his responsibilities.
嗨 手表停在了一点十五分
Hey, the watch. Stopped at 1:15.
这也符合了医生说的死亡时间
Now that agrees with the doctor on the time of death.
这是可能的 非常可能
Hmm. It is possible, yes. Certainly possible.
我还不明白
I don't quite understand.
我自己也不明白
I do not understand, myself.
我什么也不明白
I understand nothing at all.
你看看这两个伤口…
If you look at these two wounds...
他们深入皮肉 但是没什么血
they are powerful and deep, and yet there is little blood.
但是这是疯狂的捅人行动
But this was a frenzied attack.
这里一刀那里一刀的
Lashing here and there.
什么规律也没有 纯属暴力
No pattern at all, just extreme violence.
与此同时 我们的受害者
And during all this, our victim,
精力充沛精神紧绷又喝了咖啡…
vigorous and anxious and full of coffee...
只是静静的躺着等死而没有挣扎…
merely lies still and accepts death without struggle...
而且他还有这个…
when he also has here...
他应该自我防卫的工具
the means by which he might defend himself.
给你的
For you.
现在看看这里
Now, let us see here.
巴比妥：一种镇静剂
巴比妥 一种小药片
Barbital. The Mickey slipped.
他肯定被下了药昏迷了
Drugged him so he couldn't use this.
然后这里 一个女人的手帕
And later around here, a lady's handkerchief.
奢侈品 手工制作
An objet de luxe, handmade.
哇 在巴黎可是两百卢
Boom, two hundred francs in Paris.
而且还有一个大写的H
And she even has an initial, "H."
我们的朋友
And our little friend,
烟斗通条 另外的一个线索
the pipe cleaner. Another clue.
是的 各种线索总是不经意的掉出来
Yes, a riot of clues dropped most conveniently.
但是看起来只有这个烟灰缸是真的线索
Yet only one appears, however, to be perhaps genuine.
然后这个烟灰缸
And maybe this ashtray provides
带来了点面包屑
the accidental breadcrumb.
有烧焦的痕迹
A charred fragment of a note.
可能是想烧掉证据
An attempt, perhaps, to burn evidence.
谢谢 先生
Merci, monsieur.
先生我们可以借用一下你的设备吗
We may borrow your equipment, yes?
谢谢
Thank you.
Merci, merci.
现在 我想知道…
Now, I prefer to understand...
线索和物品有什么区别
why a clue is left rather than what the object is.
我们从事实本身寻找事实 并不是脱离
We seek the truth from within, not without.
但是 在这个案子里
In this case, however,
我可能需要一些科学支柱
I may welcome a little scientific assistance.
你调整火焰
You will adjust the flame.
这只是其中的一封威胁信
It's just another one of those nasty letters.
你错了 我的朋友
You are mistaken, mon ami.
这其中有一个秘密
This one has a secret to tell.
看看
Look.
身负血债 你会死
"As a strong blood is on hand, you will die."
这什么意思
What does this mean?
你跟着我
Come with me, Bouc.
让我们填补剩余的空白
Let us fill in the gaps.
这不是海滨之谜
This was never a beachside puzzle.
我知道死者的真名
I know the dead man's real name.
不是雷切特 而是卡塞蒂
It is not Ratchett, but Cassetti.
我知道这个名字
I know that name.
然后你也会知道阿姆斯壮这个名字
Then you will also know the name Armstrong.
阿姆斯壮案
The Armstrong case?
震惊世界的案件
The story shocked the world.
两年前…
Two years ago...
著名飞行员阿姆斯壮…
the renowned pilot, Colonel John Armstrong...
和他的老婆索尼亚
and his wife, Sonia,
醒来发现他们的独生女黛西…
woke to find their only child, little Daisy...
在她熟睡的时候从摇篮中被抱走了
taken from her crib as she slept.
绝望之下…
Desperate...
阿姆斯壮一家交了赎金
the Armstrongs paid the ransom.
但是不久之后 黛西被发现被…
But soon after, Daisy was found murdered by...
雷切特 当时的卡塞蒂杀死了
Ratchett, who was Cassetti.
索尼亚当时还在怀孕
Sonia Armstrong was with child
当她得知消息的时候
when she received the news.
她早产了
The shock sent her into premature labor.
她和孩子都没能活下来
Neither she nor her baby survived.
你怎么知道的 波洛
How do you know this, Poirot?
因为约翰阿姆斯壮亲自跟我说的
Because John Armstrong told me so himself.
他给我写信向我求助
He wrote to me to ask me for my help.
在我接到信之前…
By the time I received his letter...
已经太晚了
it was too late.
他被发现死于枪杀
He was found dead of a gunshot wound.
是自杀
Self-inflicted.
身负黛西阿姆斯壮的血债
"Daisy Armstrong's blood is on your hands.
你会因此而死
"You will die for it."
确实 你死了
Indeed, you did.
波洛先生 怎么了米歇尔
Monsieur Poirot? Yes, Michel.
哈伯德先生需要和你说话
Mrs. Hubbard wants to speak to you.
我尽力拖住了她
I held her as best as I could.
啊 哈伯德女士 抱歉让你久等
Ah, Mrs. Hubbard, I'm sorry to have kept you.
你思绪不绝语言不断
You have a head full of steam and a mouth full of words.
你真是太对了 我正在尝试…
You're goddamn right, I do. What I have been trying...
给你说一整天了
to tell you all day.
凶手昨晚在我的隔间里
The murderer was in my compartment last night.
我以为我会死 结果发现我应该死掉…
I thought I'd be killed. Turns out I might have been...
结果雷切特替我死了
only he got Ratchett instead.
我在黑暗中醒来 然后我知道
I woke up in the dark, and I knew
我房间有个男人
there was a man in my room.
你确定是男人
You are certain it was a man?
我知道男人在我卧室的感觉
I know what it feels like to have a man in my bedroom.
我告诉了列车员 他不信我
I told your conductor, and he wouldn't believe me.
我说 看看通讯室
I said, "Check the communication door
在我和雷切特房间中间
"Between my room and Ratchett's.
他肯定呆在那
"He must have left through there."
我绝对肯定 这个门没有拴上
Sure enough, it was unbolted.
我肯定锁了…
I know I locked it...
在与雷切特交谈之后
after what Ratchett said.
他明显的向我献殷勤
He made a rather overt overture.
可能你应该…
Have you perhaps...
听到过阿姆斯壮案
heard of the Armstrong kidnapping?
想不听说过都不行
You couldn't avoid it.
病态的事情
Morbid stuff.
杀小孩的凶手 卡赛蒂…
The child's murderer, Cassetti...
死于昨晚
died last night.
这个人是雷切特
Ratchett was the man.
我告诉你了 他一看就不是好人
I told you, I knew he was a rotten one.
你确实相信我说的…
You do believe me...
我房间里有人
about the man in my room?
我知道你觉得我蠢
I'm aware you think I'm a silly woman.
但是我有证据证明这是正确的
But I have proof it's true.
这是来自…
It is from the uniform...
东方列车列车员的制服…
of an Orient Express conductor...
但是可能是米歇尔在你房间的时候
but it might have fallen from Michel's
不小心掉下来了
when he was in your room.
我什么都没丢
I'm not missing any.
我在我床脚 在床单上
I found it
我睡觉的地方…
at the foot of my bed, on the cover...
找到的这个
right where I slept.
你管这叫什么
What do you call that?
我管这个叫做证据 太谢谢你了 哈伯德女士
I call it evidence. Thank you so much, Mrs. Hubbard.
你去过美国吗
Have you ever been to America?
去了一次
Once.
很久之前了 时间也短
Years ago, briefly.
什么目的去的
For what purpose?
- 去确认一件事  - 什么事
- To confirm a suspicion.  - Which was?
我不太喜欢说那个
That I wouldn't like it.
我在波士顿有了一份工作
I was offered a post in Boston.
我去了波士顿 然后直接回伦敦
Saw Boston, went straight back to London.
雷切特是波士顿人吗
Is that where Ratchett was from?
波士顿 我不太知道
Boston? I can't says I know.
这不太合适…
It wouldn't be proper...
去问
to ask.
继续
Carry on.
我最后看见…
I last saw...
雷切特先生是在九点钟
Mr. Ratchett at nine o'clock.
我给他端来咖啡 挂了他的衣服
I brought his coffee and hung up his clothes.
我觉得你有牙痛
You have a toothache, I think.
我预约了这周在伦敦拔牙
I've got an extraction booked in London this week.
雷切特先生坚决要求我这事别拖了
Mr. Ratchett insisted on not putting it off any longer.
他说他厌倦了
He said he was tired of hearing
听我强忍着呻吟
my suppressed groans.
这富有同情心的罗切特…
This sympathetic Ratchett...
他经常在晚上喝咖啡吗
was it his usual practice to drink coffee at night?
从不 但他最近很焦躁
Not at all. But he'd been very agitated lately.
说他想保持警觉些 尤其是在大晚上
Said he wanted to stay alert, especially so last night.
他在他房间发现了一封信
He found a letter in his compartment.
请告诉我这不是你干的
Please tell me you didn't do this.
如果我要把什么不好的东西
If I were to leave something unpleasant
放在你枕头上的话 先生…
on your pillow, sir...
那不会是一封信的
it would not be a letter.
拿咖啡来
Coffee.
当然了…
Surely, such a...
一个像你这么规矩又细心的仆人…
proper and precise valet...
不可能会这样和主人说话吧
would never speak to his master as you did?
除非他知道他的工作即将突然…
Unless he knew his career was coming to a sudden...
结束
end.
不仅是因为牙疼吧 我想
No mere toothache, I think.
是肺癌吗
The lungs?
是甲状腺癌
The thyroid.
已经蔓延到胃了
Spread now to stomach.
和我父亲一样的病 我比他还早了五年
Same as got my father, five years younger.
顶多还有几个月了
Months at best.
恐怕手术也无法治愈了 医生说
"Inoperable, I'm afraid," said the doctor.
然后突然地…我就不害怕了
And suddenly, I wasn't... afraid.
从此我只做我想做的事
I would only do what I wanted from here on.
我现在有话直说
I speak my mind now.
说说咖啡吧
The coffee.
看上去他的杯子里掺了巴比妥(镇静安眠用)
It appears that his cup was laced with barbital.
你肯定会告诉我
You, of course, will tell me
这不是你放的吧
that you did not put it in there.
当然不是我
Of course I didn't.
你是什么时候 从哪里
When and from where
取来的咖啡和杯子
did you procure the coffee and the cups?
从厨房里 先生
In the kitchen, sir.
我晚餐时点了咖啡 九点去取 我去时咖啡已准备好了
I ordered it at dinner to be ready at 9:00, and so it was.
任何人都可能在我之前对它动手脚
Anybody could have got a hold of it before me.
谢谢你的配合
Merci.
马斯特曼先生
Mr. Masterman.
对你的牙疼我感到很遗憾
I'm sorry about the toothache.
谢谢
Merci.
我喜欢小蛋糕
I love the little cakes.
那么 皮埃尔 埃斯特拉瓦多斯小姐 你是传教士…
So, Miss Pilar Estravados, you are a missionary...
但是在你改行之前
but you trained as a nurse
曾受过做护士的训练 是吗
before you changed professions, yes?
这是我欠上帝的
I owed it to God.
你有什么罪过吗
You owed Him a debt?
我曾经一度…
There were...
很放纵…
indulgent times in my life...
只知索取而不知给予
when I took more than I gave.
吉哈特 哈德曼
Gerhard Hardman.
工程学教授
Professor of engineering.
科学才能为德国
It is science that will win back
赢回他的尊严
for Germany her pride.
- 贝尼亚米诺 马奎兹  - 马奎兹先生
- Biniamino Marquez.  - Mr. Marquez.
听着 为希望你们弄清楚
Listen, I wanna be clear
我与这件案子 没有任何关系…
of any association with the crime...
所以请随意问我吧
so please ask me anything.
问什么都行 我不再撒谎了
Anything. I never lie anymore.
昨晚你离开过房间吗
Did you leave your compartment at all last night?
只离开过一次 我去拿阿司匹林
Only once, to get an aspirin.
赫伯德夫人之前给了我点药
Mrs. Hubbard offered me something earlier.
我开始拒绝了 但我睡不着时…
I declined at first, but when I couldn't rest...
我就去向她要了
I went to ask for it.
我在都灵有个会议
My conference is in Turin.
我是出席的唯一的奥地利人
I am the only Austrian to present,
也就是说 如果我不在…
which means without me...
会议就达不到标准了
the talks will be substandard.
然后我就越狱了
Then I escaped prison,
贿赂了些人 到了美国
and I bribed myself into the US.
发誓再也不撒谎盗窃了
where I swore never to lie or steal again.
因为你看 我的朋友
You see, my friends, because when people
人们信任你 就会从你这多买东西
trust you, they buy more.
意大利人就像奶牛 西班牙人像绵羊
The Italians are cows. The Spaniards, sheep.
比利时人像…
The Belgians...
我到自己房间
I come to my room, which I share
我和那英国来的闷闷不乐的男管家住
with the unhappy English butler.
那家伙 他老是呻吟
A fish. He groans a lot.
但我肯定他看着我睡了一夜到天亮
But I'm sure he saw me sleep all night until morning.
我应该要说…
I should say...
说不定与案子有关…
in case it is relevant...
有个场面很尴尬
there was an embarrassing moment.
我去看赫伯德夫人时…
When I went to see Mrs. Hubbard...
我开始开错了门
first, I opened the wrong door.
噢 抱歉
Oh, sorry.
这时是几点
What time was this?
那应该是大约…
That must have been about...
不要说抱歉
Don't be sorry.
…十点四十分
...twenty minutes to 11:00.
有意思
This is interesting.
就目前所知
As far as it is known,
你是最后一个看见雷切特活着的人
you are the last person to see Ratchett alive.
- 你做什么工作  - 推销汽车
- Your business?  - Automobiles.
我有三个展示厅
I have three showrooms.
来美国时我一无所有 现在…
I come to America with nothing. And now...
如果你说的属实
If what you say is true,
德贝纳姆小姐会证实的
Miss Debenham will confirm it.
但我说的是真的
But it is true.
我不会说谎的
I would not lie.
德贝纳姆小姐可能离开房间
May it be possible that Miss Debenham
而不被你注意到吗
left your compartment without you noticing?
不可能 我睡得很浅
No. I sleep very lightly.
听到一点点声音我都会醒来坐直
The slightest sound and I bolt upright.
我受过一次惊吓
I was surprised once.
不会有第二次了
Never again.
不 我没说我是司机
No, I didn't say I was a chauffeur.
从你行李里掉出来的照片中…
The photographs that spilled out of your luggage...
有一张很漂亮的
there was a beautiful one
上面是个戴着司机的帽子的小男孩…
with a little boy wearing a chauffeur's hat...
在看望工作中的爸爸
visiting his papa at work.
你是谁的司机
Who did you chauffeur?
埃斯特拉瓦多斯小姐 为什么你的手上
Miss Estravados, why do your hands
有拳击手该有的老茧呢
have the calluses of a boxer?
我在危险的城市工作…
I do my work in dangerous cities...
我不能被恐惧支配
where I cannot be governed by fear.
我练过拳击
I trained to fight.
但自从那次惊吓后…
But you do not trust your god anymore...
你就不在信任你的上帝了吗
since your surprise?
不 以免上帝太忙碌
No, in case He is busy.
上帝总是忙碌的
God is always busy.
是马斯特曼干的
It's Masterman.
一个濒死的人没什么可失去的
A man dying is a man with nothing to lose.
很好 布克 但是马奎兹先生…
Bravo, Bouc. Except for the problem of Mr. Marquez...
已经证实
who has now confirmed
与他同铺的马斯特曼…
that his bunkmate, Masterman...
在雷切特死亡的时候 正在床上睡觉
was reading in his bed at the time of death.
如果这么容易 我也不会出名了 下一个
If it were easy, I would not be famous. Next.
德贝纳姆小姐…
Miss Debenham...
你不介意我们在室外吹点风吧
you do not mind to brace the air?
我们为你准备了野餐
For you, we have the picnic.
却让我得室友在狭窄的车厢里受审
While you made my roommate suffer cramped quarters.
我明白了
I see.
选择最合适的地方
Choose the best location
来从不同的嫌疑人口中套出真话
to extract the truth from each suspect.
让她紧张 而让我受冻
Put her off-balance and me, freeze.
聪明
Clever.
可以请你写下你的全名
Will you write down your full name
和地址吗
and address, please?
顺便说一下 我的睡袍是淡紫色的
A pale mauve, by the way.
埃斯特拉瓦多斯小姐和我说 你问了
Miss Estravados told me you asked
她睡袍的颜色
the color of her dressing gown.
谢谢
Merci.
玛丽 赫迈奥妮 德贝纳姆
"Mary Hermione Debenham."
你被人叫做赫迈奥妮过吗
Do you ever go by Hermione?
我没被雇佣作德贝纳姆老师时 别人一直叫我玛丽
A constant Mary, when I'm not employed as Miss Debenham.
我是左撇子
Left-handed.
不大寻常 我知道
Unusual, I know.
你不能就这么妄下结论
You mustn't have your theory fixed
如果你在检查我的笔迹的话
if you're testing my handwriting.
你对死者怎么看
What did you think of the dead man?
呃 我只能说 我没怎么想过他
Uh, I can't say I did think about him.
我不太明白你问题的意义
I don't quite see the point of your question.
喔 原谅我小小的发挥 小姐
Oh, forgive me, mademoiselle, my little originalities.
人性错综复杂 总是反常的
Human nature is perverse in its complexity.
要挖掘人性 需要正确的工具
To plumb it, it takes the right tools.
这些是玩具 不是工具 赫尔克里
These are toys, not tools, Hercule.
我建议你把它们放一边吧
I prefer you put them away.
直接的办法呢 冻糕
The direct method? Parfait.
乘车之前你认识那医生吗
You knew the doctor before traveling?
阿巴斯诺特医生
Dr. Arbuthnot?
不认识
No.
却如此一见钟情吗
But such instant attraction?
我们不是在美国…
We are not in America...
德贝纳姆小姐 没有法律禁止
Miss Debenham. There are no laws
你这样的情感
against what you may feel.
也没有法律禁止我保持沉默 对此…
Nor are there laws against silence, of which...
我保持…
I hold my...
我从未去过美国
I've never been to America.
或许我可以问问一些…
Perhaps I may ask about some...
我碰巧听见的话吗
words I overheard?
你和这位陌生人 阿巴斯诺特
You and the stranger, Arbuthnot,
比陌生人的关系更亲近
are closer than strangers might be.
你说…
You said...
现在不行 等我们成了 没人能阻止我们
"Not now. When we are done. Then no one can touch us."
你是什么意思
What did you mean?
你觉得我是在说谋杀吗
You think I meant murder?
对一个拿着锤子的人来说 每个问题都是钉子
To a man with a hammer, every problem is a nail.
你活在犯罪中
You live crime.
- 你每天都目睹罪恶  - 并不是
- You see evil every day.  - Not so.
我见过足够多的犯罪
I see enough crime to know
我知道 犯罪行为是反常的
that the criminal act is the anomaly.
我相信 谋杀一个人…
I believe it takes a fracture of the soul...
会带走灵魂的一部分
to murder another human being.
我再问一遍 你的话是什么意思
I ask again, what did you mean?
我们已达成一致…
As we established...
没有法律禁止我保持沉默
there are no laws against my silence.
很好
Very well.
那么之后呢 德卓戈米罗夫公主
And afterwards, Princess Dragomiroff?
晚餐后 我上床睡觉
After dinner, I came to bed.
上帝赐我长寿
God blessed me with long life,
却给了我这带病的背 让我痛苦
but cursed me with a bad back to make it miserable.
大约十二点四十五分…
About a quarter to 1:00...
我叫来施密特小姐
I called for Fraulein Schmidt.
- 嗯哼  - 她替我按摩…
- Mmm-hmm.  - She massaged me...
给我读了一会书
and read to me for a while.
- 然后我就睡了  - 嗯哼
- Then I sleep.  - Mmm-hmm.
您和阿姆斯壮一家…
Were you ever acquainted...
熟悉吗
with a family by the name of Armstrong?
他们遭受过无法言说的不幸
They endured an unspeakable tragedy.
我很仰慕索尼娅 阿姆斯壮的母亲…
I was an admirer of Sonia Armstrong's mother...
女演员 琳达·亚登
Linda Arden, the actress.
百年难见的天才
A once-a-century talent.
亚登小姐本准备转做导演
Miss Arden was to turn to directing.
倘若没有那场悲剧
She would have become the first
百老汇：纽约市重要的南北向道路
是美国戏剧和音乐剧的重要发扬地，因此成为了音乐剧的代名词
她本能成为百老汇…
woman titan of Broadway...
第一位女巨人
were it not for the tragedy.
这位琳达·亚登 她去世了吗
And this Linda Arden, she is dead?
她要是去世了倒还好些
She might as well be.
她不再离开家
She no longer leaves her home.
黛西是我的教女
Daisy was my goddaughter.
她是个…
She was a...
我不明白这和我们的问题有什么关系 侦探先生
I don't see how this relates to our troubles, Detective.
昨晚被杀的男人 他的真名是卡塞蒂
The man killed last night, his true name was Cassetti.
他就是谋杀了黛西 阿姆斯壮的人
The man who murdered little Daisy Armstrong.
我知道了
I see.
我承认我认识这家人 现在这男人死了
I admit I know this family, and now this man is dead.
这样的巧合…
The coincidence...
一定让人难以置信
must seem unbearable.
巧合是允许出现的
You may be permitted a coincidence.
我现在要问施密特小姐几个问题
I must now ask a few questions of your Fraulein Schmidt.
不 没这个必要
No. There is no need.
我可以替她回答
I can answer to her character.
请您允许我亲自问她
Even still, if you will allow.
小姐 请你用德语回答我
Fraulein. Answer please in German.
但是公主殿下会听不懂
But her Excellency cannot comprehend me.
这才是重点
That is the point.
这是你的吗 H代表希尔德加德
This is yours? H for Hildegarde?
我不可能有这么贵重的东西
It is too fine for me.
公主说的昨晚的事属实吗
This is the truth about last night?
就像她说的一样 她让列车员来找我
As she said. She sent the conductor for me,
之后我就回床上去了
then I returned to bed.
你回去的时候有看到什么人吗
Did you see anyone when you returned?
只有另一个列车员
Only the other conductor.
另一个列车员
"The other conductor."
你是说米歇尔吗
You mean Michel?
不是 不是叫醒我的人 是另一个
No. A different one than had awoken me.
请跟我来
Please come with me.
你确定你没看到他吗
Are you sure you did not see him?
我确定 另一个列车员
I'm certain. The other conductor
长得不高 胡子很短
was a small man with a short beard.
确定吗 这里只有一个列车员
Probably, there is no other conductor.
我知道我看到了什么
I know what I saw.
我能记得是因为他的声音很高
I remember because his voice was high
而且穿着一样的制服
and the uniform was the same exactly.
不过我怀疑它少了一颗纽扣
Though, I suspect, missing one button.
先生 我需要立刻征用你的万能钥匙
Sir, I need your passkey immediately.
我们要找到一件制服和一件红色的和服
We need to find a uniform and a red kimono.
上千张照片
Thousands of photographs,
无数多的袜子…
endless pairs of socks...
除了红色之外所有颜色的睡衣都有…
dressing gowns in every color but red...
就是没有另一件制服
and still no contraband conductor's uniform.
你有检查所有乘客的行李吗
Have we checked all the passengers' luggage?
除了安德烈伯爵的行李
All except for the Count
先生
and Countess Andrenyi, monsieur.
我们不能查他们的行李
It is forbidden to search their suitcases.
他们是以外交签证出行的
They travel under diplomatic visas.
那还能是哪里呢
Where else could it be?
我们还有一件没查过的行李
There is one last suitcase we have not checked.
我的行李
My own.
凶手在嘲笑我
The killer is mocking me.
很好 他犯了第一个错误
Good. His first mistake.
因为夜晚之后就是白天…
And as the night must follow the day...
抱歉 小姐
Pardon, mademoiselle.
不 这不是我的
No, it's not mine.
我告诉过你关于列车员的事情 如果是我干的
I told you of the conductor. Why would I tell you
- 为什么我会告诉你这件事呢  - 你没有…
- if it was me?  - You would not...
这让你的房间成了最适合藏它的地方
which makes your compartment the ideal choice to hide it.
看 就是这个纽扣
Voila, the button.
如果我有一件列车员的制服…
And if a conductor's uniform...
为什么不弄一把万能钥匙呢
why not a conductor's passkey?
现在我们知道凶手是怎么
Now we know how the killer
奇迹般地把门锁上的了
magically passed through locked doors.
波本 麦奎因
Bourbon. MacQueen.
现在你在找什么
Now what are we looking for now?
五百磅
500 pounds.
麦奎因还有一个分类帐
MacQueen also had a ledger.
里面有所有他和雷切特的交易
All his dealings with Ratchett.
恩 那它在哪里呢
Where is it, hmm?
波罗
Poirot?
布克 让所有人回房间
Bouc, keep everyone inside!
先生 请你等一下
Monsieur! Please stop!
先生
Monsieur!
请你站在那里别动
Please stay where you are.
谢谢 先生 谢谢
Thank you, gentlemen. Thank you.
所以 是麦奎因吗 你找到凶手了吗
So, it was MacQueen? You have your man?
抱歉 女士
Pardonnez-moi, madame.
他怎么可以
How could he?
我没杀他
I didn't kill him!
你想要烧了雷切特的账本…
You tried to burn Ratchett's accounts...
但是他们依旧很清晰
but they are still legible in places.
数字不相符…
The maths do not tally...
因为你是从他那里偷来的
because you have been stealing from him.
这全是…
It is full of the...
用英语怎么说的 巧克力
What is the English word? The chocolat?
- 夹心  - 夹心
- Fudge?  - Fudge!
全都是巧克力夹心
It is full of the fudge!
是你从他那里拿走的
You stole from him!
你觉得暴露
You thought you would be found out.
所以你杀了他
That is why you killed him!
没错
Yeah.
没错 你对了 我从他那里偷来的
Yeah, you're damn right I stole from him.
好几千磅
Thousands.
我知道他的钱来的不干净
I knew his money wasn't honest.
我从中抽一点又有什么关系
What did it matter if I skimmed some off the top?
但是让我问你一个问题
But let me ask you a question.
为什么我要杀掉自己的财神爷
Why would I slaughter my cash cow?
我没做过
I didn't do it.
- 我没杀他  - 他不是凶手
- I didn't kill him!  - He didn't.
他不是
He didn't.
我觉得他的不在场证明和我有关
I expect his alibi revolves around me,
我们一直喝到凌晨
drinking till the early hours.
没错
Well, it's true.
我看他在和威士忌 然后
I saw him having whiskey, and remarked
评论美国酒有多难喝
on the lesser quality of American liquor.
他请我喝了一些
He offered me a tipple
想让我改变想法 之后又喝了一些
to change my mind, then another.
我们谈论政治 他对斯大林…
We got to arguing politics. He had some...
有一些意见
tomfool opinions on Stalin
我必须要纠正他 但是这个人是清白的
I had to correct. But the man knows his spirits.
我有话和你说 先生 拜托了
A word, please, monsieur.
你确定你和他在一起对吧
You can confirm you were with him all night?
没错 我们抽烟聊天一直到两点
We smoked and spoke till nearly 2:00, yes.
他和他的香烟 和你…
Ah, such chums, him with his cigarettes, and you...
是的 你是火车上唯一一个用烟斗的人
Yes, you are the only man on the train who smokes a pipe.
我可以看看你的烟斗和烟草吗
May I see your pipe and your tobacco, please?
当然可以
Of course.
而你 阿巴斯诺特医生
And you, Dr. Arbuthnot,
我想你是从印度来的对吧
were traveling from India, I believe. Yes?
你现在开始问我了吗 嗯
You're interviewing me now? Mmm-hmm.
在雷切特死之前
Were you ever in Ratchett's compartment
- 你去过他车厢吗  - 当然没有
- before he was killed?  - Certainly not.
但是这是你的烟斗清洁棒 不是吗
But this is one of your pipe cleaners, n'est-ce pas?
如果你是在他的车厢里找到的 问问别人吧
If you found that in the dead man's cabin, look elsewhere.
先生 我是个医生
I am a doctor, sir.
我是救人的 不是杀人的
I heal people. I do not hurt them.
关于这个 你为了成为医生
About this, see, you must have worked
一定非常认真的学习了
very hard to become a doctor.
你的人种里没有多少人有这样的机会
Not many of your race are allowed the opportunity.
米德尔赛克斯医学院每个班会招一个人
Middlesex Medical College permits one per class.
我有幸在一九二四年入学了
I had the honor in '24.
我服役时是一个狙击手
I was a sniper in my tour.
一个神枪手
A sharpshooter.
救了一些人
Saved more than a few officers.
他们很感激我
The more grateful,
肯定了我的技术…
recognized a fair mind with a steady hand...
并且资助了我的学业
and supported my education.
我不能让他们的慷慨白费
I take their generosity as a debt.
你认识阿姆斯壮上校吗
Did you know a Colonel Armstrong?
我知道两三个阿姆斯壮
Might have known two or three Armstrongs.
六十年代的汤米 塞尔比·阿姆斯壮…
Tommy in the 60th... Selby Armstrong...
不 我是说约翰 阿姆斯壮上校
No, I meant Colonel John Armstrong.
他有一个美国妻子
He had an American wife,
他的孩子被绑架并且杀害了
and his child was kidnapped and killed.
哦
Oh.
不认识
Never came across the fellow.
你第一次见到德贝纳姆小姐是什么时候
When did you first meet Miss Debenham?
是从基尔库克到尼西比时
We met when we shared the railway convoy car
我们一起坐铁路车队车的时候
from Kirkuk to Nissibin.
她和我不一样
She claims otherwise,
她让自己非常可疑
and she has made herself problematically suspicious.
抱歉
Excusez-moi.
玛丽是一个淑女
Mary is a lady.
别把她牵扯进来 我可以为她的人格担保
Leave her out of this. I can vouch for her character.
就像你为麦奎因的时间线担保一样吗
As you vouched for MacQueen's time?
你一定不会想要知道原因的
You won't listen to reason. Never.
你很幸运 好医生坚持说
You are lucky. The good doctor insists
你从未离开他的视线
he did not let you out of his sight.
看吧 我不是凶手
See? There. Couldn't have done it.
是的 你就是的
Yes, you could.
雷切特每晚都会吃一片安眠药
Ratchett took a sleeping draught each evening.
你很容易就可以在里面加巴比妥
You could add barbital, easily access that drug.
就像在医生的酒里下药一样…
Do the same with one of the doctor's many drinks...
很明显你有机会可以去杀他
and the chance to kill him is clear.
为什么我要这么做
Why would I do any of that?
我们已经想到了你的动机
We have established your motive.
或许我可以提出另外一点
Perhaps I will suggest a different one.
一个不一样的原因 更加私人的原因
A different reason, a more personal reason.
一个靠教育而非性格的律师
"A lawyer by education, not by disposition."
我想知道为什么你要学法律
Why did you pursue the law, I wonder?
是为了一个深爱的
Was it to appease a much loved,
但是希望子承父业的父亲…
but demanding father...
他在同样的领域
one who himself had made a great success
也很成功…
in the same field...
之后却失去了他的地位
and then lost his position?
麦昆曾经很有名 不是吗
There was a renowned MacQueen, was there not?
新泽西的区域律师…
The district attorney for the state of New Jersey...
为阿姆斯壮一案
responsible for the prosecution
做检察官
of the Armstrong case.
他们没有嫌疑人
They didn't have a suspect.
我的父亲压力巨大
My dad was pressured to go after
在这个可怜的法国女人…
this poor French woman...
一个柔弱的女佣之后？
a maid with a weak alibi, Susanne.
他把整个案子都退给女佣
He hung his whole case on her.
她就自杀了
She killed herself.
她是无辜的
She was innocent.
当证据指向卡塞蒂的时候
By the time the evidence lead to Cassetti,
哦 他早已去世了
oh, he was long gone.
他们败坏了他的名声
They tore my old man apart.
我不能为他做任何事
I couldn't do anything for him.
所以你说
And yet you claim
你不知道雷切特就是卡塞蒂
that you did not know Ratchett was Cassetti?
不 不
No, no.
但是你找到他了
But you found him.
没有
No.
你找到他了
You found him.
- 你榨干了他…  - 没有
- You bled him dry...  - No.
为了给你父亲报仇
in order to settle your father's debts,
最后 完成计划
and then finally, to settle the score.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
不 不是…
No. It wasn't...
不是这样的 不是这样的…
It wasn't like that. It's not the way...
有人闯了进来…
Someone kicked in the door...
医生
Doctor!
蒙住了我的脸
covered my face.
好吧 这个要立刻拔出来
All right, this needs to come out now.
- 我需要我的包  - 当然
- I want my bag.  - Of course.
在我的车厢里
It's in my compartment.
这样不会留下指纹
There will be no fingerprints.
凶手要销毁杀人凶器
The killer was disposing of the murder weapon.
在这儿
It's there!
凶手没有刺中肺或者动脉
The killer didn't hit a lung or artery.
她能活下来真是幸运
She's lucky to be alive.
你们都很幸运
You all are.
是啊 天才
Yeah, some genius!
为什么你还不破案
Why haven't you solved this case?
要给他些时间
You must give the man some time.
是啊…
Yeah, well...
我等不下去了 我要死了
I can't give that much more. I don't have any blood left.
是啊
Yeah.
你们询问麦奎因先生
Accosting Mr. MacQueen,
然而真正的凶手就在这里
and the real killer is right here.
你们中的一员
One of you people.
我不知道你是谁 我什么都没说
I don't know who you are. I said nothing.
拜托 别来搞我
Please, leave me alone.
朋友们 早上轨道就会被清理干净
My friends, the tracks will be cleared by morning.
拜托 回房间去
Please, return to your rooms.
我要在这里睡…
I'm sleeping here...
我们互相都可以看到的地方
where everyone can see me and I can see everyone.
你们都应该这么做 这样比较暖
You should all do the same. Conserve heat.
请大家待在视野开阔 安全的地方 直到早上
Remain in the open, safely in view, until morning.
凶手要再杀人的话可是不会犹豫的
A killer will never hesitate to kill again.
不管他有没有外交豁免权…
I will convey the same message to the Andrenyis...
我都会告诉他同样的话
diplomatic immunity or not.
如果可以的话 我想看看你的护照
If I may, I will look at your passports.
你知道我必须要和她聊聊
You know that I must talk with her.
还有 你的妻子的名字上有块油斑
By the way, there is a grease spot on your wife's name.
你或许想看看
You might want to look at that.
伊莲娜不太好
Elena is not well.
如果你不要我这么做的话
If you do not permit me, your reluctance
我会告诉南斯拉夫警方你不合作…
will be noted to the Yugoslav Police...
而且我不确定他们会不会把你们都抓起来…
and I have no doubt that they will arrest both you and...
你怎么可以
How dare you!
亲爱的
Darling!
Darling.
波罗先生 你看起来真好笑
You are funny-looking, monsieur Poirot.
所有侦探都长的这这么好笑吗
Are all detectives so funny-looking?
很抱歉叫醒你 康科斯夫人
I am sorry to wake you, Madame la Comtesse.
嗯
Hmm.
我总是在夜晚醒着
I am always awake at night.
在白天睡觉
In the day, I sleep.
有些怕黑 但我忍受不了光
Some fear darkness, but I cannot stand the light.
你总是服用…
You are always under the influence of...
巴比妥
Barbital.
巴比妥：一种镇静剂
巴比妥 巴比妥
Barbital, barbital.
我会服用很多
I take oceans of it.
哦 撒谎是没用的 亲爱的
Oh, there's no use in a lie, love.
他能看透我们
He can see right through us.
我不能出门不带它
I cannot go outside without it.
没有它我睡不着
I cannot sleep without it.
我用它来驱赶恐惧
I take it against my fears.
你的恐惧是什么
What are you afraid of?
一切
Everything.
你护照上显示你本名戈登堡
Your passport has your maiden name as Goldenberg.
犹太人 是吗
Jewish, yes?
并不是纯犹太人 我的中间名不是玛丽亚
Not so Jewish. My middle name isn't Maria.
那你和你丈夫一样是舞者吗
And you are a dancer like your husband?
不 和我丈夫不一样
No, not like my husband.
在芭蕾舞团
Corps de ballet.
他被天使触碰过
He is touched by angels.
我通过热情和
I have been shoved by passion
努力变得能胜任
and hard work to become adequate.
不好意思 我必须去躺着了
Excuse me, I must lie down again.
这是你唯一的一件睡衣吗
Is this your only dressing gown?
不 我还有一件 玉米色的雪纺衫
No, I have another. Corn-colored chiffon.
我喜欢和侦探聊天
I like speaking to detectives.
你永远不知道他们接下来要问什么
You never know what they're going to ask you next.
我对首都特别擅长
I'm particularly good at capitals.
我的女家教对地理十分热衷
My governess was a stickler for geography.
你满意了吗
Are you satisfied?
我总会因为发现说谎者而感到满足
I am always satisfied when I uncover a liar.
夫人 你的名字不是艾琳娜 而是海伦娜
Madame, your name is not Elena. It is Helena.
尽管你笨拙地尝试去
Despite your clumsy attempts
在你的行李上改动它
to change it here and on your luggage.
我丈夫听说
My husband heard
发现了一些证据…
of a piece of evidence found...
一块刺绣着H的手帕
a handkerchief embroidered with an "H,"
他不想让我因为H被牵连
and didn't want my "H" Involved.
所以我们做了手脚 行李还有护照
So we changed it. The luggage and the passport.
想要摆脱麻烦并不等同于犯罪
It's no crime to want to be distant from trouble.
是 但问题就是
Yet, here is trouble.
一个令人好奇的细节是
A curious detail
在阿姆斯壮惨案中…
about the Armstrong tragedy at the heart of this case...
有多少人受到了伤害
is how many people were wounded by it.
妹妹
The younger sister.
作为演员的母亲…
The actress mother...
艺名为 雅顿·琳达
stage name, Linda Arden.
诚挚地感谢您睿智的来信　雅顿·琳达
我猜她的祖先也是犹太人…
I suppose she, too, was of Jewish ancestry...
那么谁最有可能有一个艺名
as who is most likely to take a stage name?
就无法推测了…
Is it too far to suggest...
她的原名是戈登堡
her original name was Goldenberg?
尤其是我们发现了一位年轻的女士
Especially when we find a young woman,
年龄相仿…
the same age...
作为她幸存的女儿…
as her surviving daughter...
生活在恐惧之中
living in a world of fear?
他的妹妹 索尼亚 阿姆斯特朗
The sister of Sonia Armstrong.
出去
Get out!
我听到声音就跑过来了 刚刚好 是吗
I hear noises and I run. Just in time, yes?
你现在一定认为伯爵和伯爵夫人是凶手
You must now believe the count and countess are the killers.
伯爵是自我防卫
The count is protective.
伯爵夫人连房间里的一只蜘蛛都杀不死
The countess would no sooner kill a bedroom spider.
你不用再装了
And you may desist with this charade.
你既不是奥地利人也不是德国人 更不是什么教授
You are neither an Austrian, nor a German, nor a professor.
而是一位出色的模仿者
But a good imitation.
是模仿了某个你认识的人吗
Was it based on someone you know?
我出生地的一位德国屠夫
A local butcher where I grew up was a Kraut.
一个好人 纯正的口音
Good man, great accent.
为什么这么说
What was it?
都灵：意大利城市
你说了 都灵…
You said "Tur-in..."
重音的音节不对
the emphasis on the wrong syllable
一个正统的日耳曼人会说
for a proud and proper Teuton.
都灵
"Tu-reen."
你十分敏锐 我承认
You are one sharp knife, I give you that.
格哈德哈德曼教授…
Herr Professor Gerhard Hardman...
是我的假名
is my cover.
抱歉上演了一出种族歧视的戏码
I'm sorry about the colored folks cracks.
我也算半个犹太人
Hell, I'm half a Heeb myself.
塞勒斯 贝思曼 哈德曼
Cyrus Bethman Hardman.
你是平克顿的侦探
You are a Pinkerton detective?
三十年
30 years.
当时我在斯坦布尔 刚做完一个任务
I was in Stamboul, coming back from a job,
接到了公司的电报
when the office cabled.
雷切特需要一个人保护他
Ratchett asked for a man to tail him,
出三倍的价格
offering triple time.
而我就是那个人
Lucky me being nearby.
他让我注意
He told me to look out
一个矮的 声音很尖的黑人
for a small, dark man with a high voice.
我整晚都…
I watched that hall...
从门缝盯着走廊
all night through a crack in my door.
任何刺客…
Any thug...
都会先经过我
had to go by me first.
我发誓这是真的
I'll take my oath on it.
那你是否愿意发誓…
And would you also take your oath...
你做了三十年侦探…
on your thirty years as a Pinkerton Detective...
还是继续向我撒谎…
or would you lie to me again...
然后否认你是一个警察
and deny that you were, in fact, a policeman first?
你的枪 枪托上的格纹 蓝色的漆面…
Your gun, the checkered grip, the blue finish...
是特警用的
produced for the Police Positive edition.
一九二七年的
1927 issue.
看来你为我准备了
It appears there are no end to the lies
一箩筐的谎言
manufactured just for me.
把枪留下你可以走了 教授
You can leave your gun as you go, Professor.
从他车厢的位置…
From the position of his cabin...
是不可能错过的
it would have been impossible to miss.
除非雷切特的门是开着的…
Unless Ratchett's door was open...
正如皮拉尔 埃斯特拉瓦多斯说她开了
as Pilar Estravados claims she opened it.
这样的话 就有人可能…
In which case, someone could have been...
逃脱他的视线
masked from his view.
我亲爱的凯瑟琳
My darling Katherine.
这起惨案…
This is an abominable crime...
我陷入了困境 凯瑟琳
and I am stuck, ma Katherine.
我无法找到破绽
I cannot find the crack in the wall.
为什么他们中有人迷惑了我
Why does one of them elude me?
我一直都…
I have always been...
很笃定
so sure.
太笃定
Too sure.
但现在 我就像一个孩子一样
But now, I am very humble.
谦卑地说…
And I say, like a little child...
我不知道
I do not know.
我恨害怕 凯瑟琳
I am afraid, ma Katherine.
女士们先生们 我很抱歉
My apologies, ladies and gentlemen.
当在装引擎的时候
It is not safe on board
在列车上不安全
whilst the engine is put back on the tracks.
我们去隧道那边等一下 谢谢
We are to wait in the tunnel. Thank you.
他们要把狗带到哪里去
Where are they taking the dogs?
他们会很开心的
They'll be happy.
不会的
That's not right.
只是伸了伸腿 很好
Just to stretch their legs, it's good.
不 不对
No, that's not right.
冷死了
It's freezing!
我们是困住了吗
Are we stuck?
你找我吗
You asked for me?
又要审讯吗
Another interrogation?
哦不 我非常开心有你的陪伴
Oh, no. I enjoy your company.
谢谢你 布克
Merci, Bouc.
啊 请坐
Uh, please.
我这里列了十个 我无法解答的问题…
I have a list of ten questions I am no nearer to answering...
这列车就要开了
and the train is about to leave.
你很聪明…
You have a clear mind...
我认为你可能可以看出点什么 请
and I thought that you might produce an insight. Please.
呃
Hmm.
手绢 烟斗通条
"The handkerchief. The pipe cleaner.
红色和服 制服
"The scarlet kimono. The uniform.
手表上的时间
"The time on the watch.
谋杀发生在当时 之前还是之后
"Was he murdered then? Earlier or later?
被一个人杀害还是多个人
"By one person or more?
哪些人
"Which of them?"
不好意思 我无法帮助你
Sorry, I can't help you.
呃…谢谢你
Uh... Merci.
大概还有第十一个疑问
Perhaps there is an eleventh question
你现在不知道…
you don't know to ask yet...
它会为你解答其他所有问题
that will give you the answer to the rest.
也许吧
Perhaps.
我可以轻易地说安德烈伯爵夫人
I could point an easy finger at the, uh, Countess Andrenyi.
我发现她是索尼亚 阿姆斯特朗的妹妹
I discovered she was Sonia Armstrong's sister.
- 你确定吗  - 确定
- Are you certain?  - Yes.
我估计她大概是清白的
I suspect she may perhaps be innocent.
只是可能
Perhaps.
但是列车上的很多人都
But so many people have lied to me
有意无意地对我撒了谎
on this train and do not seem to mind.
而你做得毫不费力
You yourself did so effortlessly.
我
Me?
你曾告诉我你从未去过美国
You told me you had never been to America.
你同样隐藏了
You also concealed the fact
当阿姆斯特朗惨案发生时…
that at the time of the tragedy...
你就在他家担任…
you were living in the Armstrong household...
她们女儿家教的事实
as governess to their daughter.
你也知道这一切
And you know this.
我也要生存
I have my living to get.
一个牵连进谋杀案的女人…
A girl detained in connection to a murder case...
不会有其他人愿意雇佣我的
no decent class family would engage me.
德贝纳姆小姐 是你一手策划了对雷切特的谋杀
Miss Debenham, you planned Ratchett's murder.
然后你让伯爵夫人作为证人
And then you sent for the countess to witness it.
如果她看见他死了
If she saw him dead,
那个你认识的海琳娜就可能回来
the Helena you knew might return.
你想等你的室友睡着 但她没有
You waited for your roommate to sleep, but she did not.
你给她下了药
You drugged her.
但巴比妥只让她头疼
But the barbital only gave her a headache.
当列车停下的时候她要了阿司匹林
She begged for an aspirin when the train stopped,
列车员去了站台…
when the conductor was on the station...
周围没了人…
when the coast was clear at last...
你终于有机会在没人能
when you were allowed to enter
发现的时候进入雷切特的房间
Ratchett's compartment, unseen.
你爱黛西 阿姆斯特朗 是你杀了卡塞蒂
You loved Daisy Armstrong. You killed Cassetti.
卡塞蒂就是一头畜生
Cassetti was a pig.
他该死
He deserved to die.
她没有杀他
She didn't kill him.
我杀的
I did.
玛丽 快走
Mary, go.
我不会让你因为…
I can't let you take the blame...
我一人的罪行而被指控
for what I did alone.
玛丽 求你了 走吧
Mary, please, go.
约翰 阿姆斯特朗是我最好的朋友
John Armstrong was my best friend,
我的指挥官
my commander.
他十分信任我
He believed in me.
他送我去了医学院 给了我未来
He sent me to medical school, gave me a future.
卡塞蒂把他给毁了
Cassetti destroyed him.
悲哀中 我认识了玛丽
In grief, I found Mary.
然后发现了雷切特
Then I found Ratchett.
我们本来计划向警察揭发他
Our plan was to reveal him to the police,
正如你之前所听到的
that's what you heard.
但每当我看见他的脸…
But when I saw his face...
我知道他不配受到审判
I knew he didn't deserve a trial.
所以是你对麦奎因下了药
So, you drugged MacQueen.
你拨动了表上的时间…
You changed the time on the watch...
以至于你能捏造死亡时间
so that you could lie about the time of death.
我不能让你指控玛丽
I couldn't let Mary be accused.
或者麦昆
Or MacQueen.
我犯的罪我一人承担
My sins are mine to pay for, alone.
我是一名军人
I'm a soldier.
军人为了保护而杀人
A soldier kills to protect.
但是现在 波洛先生
And now, Mr. Poirot,
我必须保护自己
I must protect myself from you.
你为什么还不死
Why aren't you dead yet?
波洛
Poirot?
先生们 停一下
Gentlemen, stop!
先生 我们要让所有乘客
Sir, we need to get all the passengers
都回到车上
back on the train.
在我让你们回来之前…
You will retire...
你们都不能…
away from the train...
继续回到火车上
until I tell you to return.
你们说的谎言…
You tell your lies...
以为没有人能看穿
and you think no one will know.
但有两个人会知道
But there are two people who will know.
是的 两个人
Yes, two people.
上帝…
Your God...
和赫尔克里 波洛
and Hercule Poirot.
是时候解决这个案子了
It is time to solve this case.
阿布思诺医生问我为什么还不死
Dr. Arbuthnot asked me why I was not yet dead.
他当然知道答案
He knew, of course, the answer.
神枪手这么近距离却没有杀人
A sharpshooter who does not kill at close range?
你不是失手开枪 你在帮我
Your shot was not a mistake. It was a surgery.
你下不了手 因为你不是杀手
You could not kill me because you are no killer.
你们全都不是杀手
None of you are killers.
但是 一定有人是
And yet, someone must be.
这件案子有两种可能的答案
There are two possible solutions to this crime.
一种很难 因为它符合了大部分的
One difficult, because it fits with most
却不是全部的事实…
but not all of the facts...
另一种…
and one more...
很复杂
complex.
第一种答案
The first solution.
雷切特有敌人
Ratchett had enemies.
罪恶的黑手党在温科夫齐偷偷潜上火车…
A rogue Mafioso steals onto the train at Vinkovci...
趁着麦奎因和阿巴斯诺特下车透气的时候
as MacQueen and Arbuthnot take the air.
带着一套制服
Equipped with a uniform
还有万能钥匙 他刺死了雷切特
and a passkey, he stabs Ratchett.
通过赫伯德女士的隔间离开
He leaves through Mrs. Hubbard's compartment,
然后逃跑
and makes his escape.
不
No.
不 不 不 这不成立
No, no, no. It doesn't work.
那为什么把制服藏起来
Why hide the uniform, hmm?
谁给雷切特下了药
Who drugs Ratchett?
谁刺伤了赫伯德女士
Or stabs Mrs. Hubbard?
搞错了 老天
Damn it, man!
所以我才问 这对谁有好处
So I ask, who stands to benefit?
这是对谋杀者的谋杀
This crime is the murdering of a murderer.
这好处 或许是…
The benefit is, perhaps...
缓解痛苦 安慰灵魂
to the spirit, an ease of suffering.
让脑子里让人无法安眠
To quiet a shouting voice
的喊叫声平息
in the head that prevents sleep.
我们中有一个杀人犯
There is a murderer among us.
那么…
So...
我们有阿巴斯诺特医生
We have Dr. Arbuthnot,
阿姆斯特朗上校忠诚而可爱的朋友
a dedicated, grateful friend to Colonel Armstrong.
他认识了玛丽 德贝纳姆
He meets and finds solace
并在这位家庭女教师的陪伴中找到慰藉…
in the company of the governess, Mary Debenham...
她和那小女孩亲如母女
who is almost like a mother to the little girl.
同样有阿姆斯特朗女士的妹妹
And so close to Mrs. Armstrong's young sister,
赫莲娜 戈登伯格…
Helena Goldenberg...
嫁给了一个有权有势的男人
married to a powerful man
一个狂暴的男人
no stranger to rage and violence.
我们还和黛西的教母…
We travel also with Daisy's godmother...
那印有首字母的…
to whom belongs...
在犯罪现场找到的
the monogrammed handkerchief
手帕就属于她
found at the scene of the crime.
字母 H 在俄文中
The letter "H" In the Russian alphabet,
当然 发音作 N
of course, pronounced "N."
娜塔莉亚 德拉戈米诺夫
Natalia Dragomiroff.
还有她那忠心耿耿的女仆 有着厨师的眼睛
And her devoted maid with a chef's eye?
在这之前她是谁呢
Who was she before her current employ?
我能猜是阿姆斯特朗家的厨师吗
Might I suggest the Armstrongs' cook?
到这里还没有结束
But we are not yet done.
照顾黛西的护士…
The nurse in charge of Daisy...
她新的宗教热情
her newfound religious zeal
是源于照管不周使她被带走的悔恨…
born of guilt at allowing her charge...
是你 那天晚上…
to be abducted. It was you, was it not...
在她房间里
in her room the night when
当雷切特从窗户进来的时候
Ratchett came in through the window?
你是不是那天晚餐的时候
Did you have a glass of wine too many
喝了太多的酒
with your supper that night?
你是否从此怪罪自己…
Have you blamed yourself ever since...
因为没有及时警醒阻止他
for not being alert to stop him?
她是那么天真无邪…
She knew nothing but kindness...
那么有爱 直到…
and love, until...
直到我…
until I...
不用猜了 先生
No need to divine with me, sir.
我是阿姆斯特朗上校在战场上的勤务兵
I was Colonel Armstrong's batman in the war.
在那以后 是他在纽约的仆从
And afterwards, his valet in New York.
他是上帝创造的最好的人
As fine a man as God ever made.
他的私人司机同意吗
Would his chauffeur agree?
是不是阿姆斯特朗担保的银行贷款
Was it a bank loan, secured by Armstrong,
让他能够创造自己的汽车帝国
allows him to build his automobile empire?
他一生都感激这份帮助 我们还能指望谁呢
He's indebted for life. Who else can we count?
比如说 便衣侦探
What of the Pinkerton detective,
曾经是负责…
once a police officer...
阿姆斯特朗案的警察
assigned to the Armstrong case?
他爱上了某个人
And he becomes attached to someone,
这就是案子里另一个无人关心的受害者
for there is another, uncelebrated victim.
你爱上了那女仆
You fell in love with the maid
在她被歪曲地指控之前
before she was falsely accused.
你眼看着正义被歪曲…
You quit the police when you witnessed...
眼看着麦奎因的父亲执意逮捕她…
the travesty of justice...
眼看着她自尽
when MacQueen's father insisted on her arrest.
于是辞去了警察的职务
When she took her own life.
不 不 不
No! No, no!
苏珊是那么温柔
Susanne was so gentle.
她喜欢上我
And she fell for me.
一个糟老头
Old and already getting grey.
我告诉她会有更好的人…
I told her she could do better...
但她就在那儿…
but there she was...
每次约会准时出现
on time for every date.
为什么一列火车…
Why else is a train...
装满了冬天的死亡 为什么伤口完全不一致
so full in the dead of winter? Why the inconsistent wounds?
为什么有如此多证据 为什么…
Why the abundance of evidence? Why...?
为什么列车员
Why the conductor?
阿维尼翁的皮埃尔 米歇尔…
Pierre Michel of Avignon...
失去了他的姐姐…
who lost his sister...
苏珊 米歇尔…
the accused maid...
被控诉的女仆
Susanne Michel.
只有一个人
Only one soul can claim to have lost
比你们任何人失去的更多
more than any of you.
可怜的琳达·亚登…
The tragic Linda Arden...
索菲亚的妈妈…
mother of Sonia...
黛西的祖母
grandmother of Daisy.
从舞台退休前…
Retired from the stage...
最后一次表演
but for one final performance.
你真是聪明到可怕
You're an awfully clever man.
谋杀有一个受害者
A murder should have one victim.
当雷切特杀害黛西 阿姆斯特朗的时候…
When Ratchett kills Daisy Armstrong...
许多的生命被破坏 变得扭曲 甚至终结
a dozen lives are broken, deformed, ended.
他们想要正义
They demand justice!
在所有这些受伤的灵魂中 我们最终必须回答…
Of all these wounded souls, we must finally answer...
他们中的谁才是杀人者
who among them is a killer?
谁拿起了刀 答案是…
Who takes up the knife? The answer is...
你们中的任何一个人都不能单独完成
No single one of you could have done it.
一对人 也不行
Nor any pair.
只有你们所有人一起…
It can only have been done...
才能完成
by all of you.
一起完成
Together.
一起
即使雪崩改变了一切…
Even when the avalanche changes everything...
侦探的出现也改变了一切 你们改变了计划
as does the detective, plans must change.
那和服 制服
The kimono, the uniform.
令人赞叹的随机应变
A remarkable improvisation,
知道如何刺伤而不杀死他的医生
the doctor who knows how to wound without killing.
每个人都都有自己的角色
Each has their part to play.
动手
Do it.
这是我计划的
It was my plan.
我召集了他们
I recruited them.
我让哈德曼追踪卡赛蒂
I had Hardman track down Cassetti.
我让麦奎因去为他工作
I sent MacQueen to work for him,
然后马斯特曼也去了
and then Masterman.
麦奎因可以安排他
MacQueen could arrange
乘坐米歇尔当值那天的专列
he travel on the day that Michel was on duty.
雷切特先生
Mr. Ratchett?
没事
It's nothing.
好的 先生 晚安
Bien, monsieur. Good night.
于是一切都完成了
And so it is done.
为了无辜的死者
For the death of the innocent.
一命偿一命
A life for a life.
复仇
Revenge.
除了我没有人应该被绞刑
No one should hang for this but me.
都是我的计划
It was my plan!
告诉警察是我一个人做的
Tell the police it was me, alone.
我的生命中再也没有别人了
There's no life left in me anymore.
而他们还有机会
They have a chance now.
赫莲娜 我求求你…
Helena, I pray...
他们有机会
has a chance.
他们可以…
They can...
继续活着…
go live...
享受快乐…
find some joy...
去别的地方
somewhere.
在我这里结束吧
Let it end with me.
他们不是杀人犯
They're not killers.
他们是好人
They're good people.
他们还是好人
They can be good again.
这世上有对 有错
There was right, there was wrong.
这些造就了你
Now there is you.
我无法评判这些
I cannot judge this.
你们必须自己决定
You must decide.
你们想要不为这犯罪
You wish to go free
而受罚…
without punishment for your crime...
你们只需要再犯一件
then you must only commit one more.
我不会阻止你们
I will not stop you.
你不能让他们杀你
You can't let them kill you.
你们把我的尸体沉到湖里
You give my body to the lake,
然后在下一站清白地离开
and you walk away innocent at the station.
你们必须让我沉默
You must silence me.
布克可以撒谎
Bouc can lie.
我不行
I cannot.
动手吧 任何一个人
Do it! One of you!
不要
Don't.
黛西死的时候我就死了
I already died with Daisy.
不
No!
你说你是为了寻找正义
You said your role was to find justice.
在这里 正义是什么
What is justice here?
有时候 人类的法律并不足够
Sometimes, the law of man is not enough.
那良知何在
Where does conscience lie?
随着黛西埋葬了
Buried with Daisy.
亲爱的阿姆斯特朗上校
My dear Colonel Armstrong.
我终于可以回你的信了…
Finally, I can answer your letter...
我相信在某处 你能听到我
at least with the thoughts in my head
脑中的想法…
and the feeling in my heart...
心中的感受
that somewhere, you can hear me.
我现在发现了
I have now discovered
案子的真相 它令我…
the truth of the case, and it is...
相当困扰
profoundly disturbing.
我见识过人类灵魂的分崩离析
I have seen the fracture of the human soul.
那么多残破的生命 那么多痛苦和愤怒…
So many broken lives, so much pain and anger...
都比不上深沉悲痛的毒害…
giving way to the poison of deep grief...
让一件谋杀变成更多谋杀
until one crime became many.
我总是想相信
I have always wanted to believe
人类是理智而文明的
that man is rational and civilized.
我的存在就寄托在…
My very existence depends upon this hope...
秩序 方法 以及小小的脑细胞上
upon order and method and the little gray cells.
但现在 或许 我应该…
But now, perhaps, I am asked...
去聆听…
to listen, instead...
内心的声音
to my heart.
女士们先生们…
Ladies and gentlemen...
在这件案子中我明白 正义的尺度…
I have understood in this case that the scales of justice...
并不总是能被平衡地度量的
cannot always be evenly weighed.
我必须学会至少一次…
And I must learn, for once...
忍受世界的不平衡
to live with the imbalance.
这里没有杀人者
There are no killers here.
只有值得被治愈的人们
Only people who deserve a chance to heal.
警察们接受了
The police have accepted
我对这起案子的第一个解释…
my first solution to the crime...
只有一个逃逸了的杀手
the lone assassin who made his escape.
我将在这里下车完成一些手续
I will leave the train here to conclude formalities.
你们都自由了
You are all free to go.
希望你们能找到内心的平和
And may you find your peace with this.
希望我们都可以
May we all.
你好
Hello.
我在找波洛先生
I'm looking for a Mr. Poirot.
有急事找他
He's needed on a very urgent matter.
啊 他在度假呢
Ah. He is on holiday.
还是卡斯诺的案子吗
The, uh, Kassner case again?
不是的 先生 比那更糟
No, sir, far worse.
我必须直接把他带到埃及
I have to take him to Egypt straight away.
有一起谋杀 先生 就在该死的尼罗河边
There's been a murder, sir, right on the bloody Nile.
你是那位侦探吗
Are you the detective?
是的
Yes.
我就是
I am the detective.
你能拉直自己的领带吗
Could you please straighten your tie?
车上见
I will see you at the car.
来 先生
Here you are, sir.
谢谢
Merci.
走吧
Allons-y.